<descriptions>
  <room id="001">
    <desc>Room 1W comprises two subunits, 1W and 2W. The larger Chacoan era room was initially defined as 1W. Once the San Juan subdividing wall was encountered, excavators retained the name 1W for the east half and designated the west half as 2W. 1W is located in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and measures 3.6 x 3.3 m. Nineteen strata were designated. Four separate floor units were identified, along with fill sequences, structured trash deposits, and roof-fall strata. Two, possibly three, Chacoan floors were present in 1W. Six features were discovered in Room 1W. Because Rooms 1W, 2W, and 5W do not follow the typical Chacoan room suite pattern and were built at the end of the west wing, they appear to represent an add-on to the original design. A later, partial San Juan period burial was placed into the Chacoan deposits of this room. No tree-ring dates comes from Room 1W but its masonry style and ceramics indicate construction during the Chacoan interval.</desc>
    <unit id="001W">
      <desc>Room 1W comprises two subunits, 1W and 2W. The larger Chacoan era room was initially defined as 1W. Once the San Juan subdividing wall was encountered, excavators retained the name 1W for the east half and designated the west half as 2W. 1W is located in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and measures 3.6 x 3.3 m. Nineteen strata were designated. Four separate floor units were identified, along with fill sequences, structured trash deposits, and roof-fall strata. Two, possibly three, Chacoan floors were present in 1W. Six features were discovered in Room 1W. Because Rooms 1W, 2W, and 5W do not follow the typical Chacoan room suite pattern and were built at the end of the west wing, they appear to represent an add-on to the original design. A later, partial San Juan period burial was placed into the Chacoan deposits of this room. No tree-ring dates comes from Room 1W but its masonry style and ceramics indicate construction during the Chacoan interval.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="002">
    <desc>Room 2W is the western portion of a large subdivided Chacoan room; Room 1W is the eastern half. The room is located along the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and measures 3.6 x 3.3 m. m. Room 2W was excavated from the years 1970-1973. Five strata were recorded including at least one floor. Three features were associated with Room 2W: foundation footings, a doorway in the west wall, and a San Juan burial dating after 1200. The room was probably used for storage during the Chacoan period. No tree-ring dates were obtained from Room 2W, but the masonry style and construction techniques in evidence, as well as ceramic data, support construction of the room during the 1090–1094 interval.</desc>
    <unit id="002W">
      <desc>Room 2W is the western portion of a large subdivided Chacoan room; Room 1W is the eastern half. The room is located along the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and measures 3.6 x 3.3 m. m. Room 2W was excavated from the years 1970-1973. Five strata were recorded including at least one floor. Three features were associated with Room 2W: foundation footings, a doorway in the west wall, and a San Juan burial dating after 1200. The room was probably used for storage during the Chacoan period. No tree-ring dates were obtained from Room 2W, but the masonry style and construction techniques in evidence, as well as ceramic data, support construction of the room during the 1090–1094 interval.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="004">
    <desc>Room 4W is an original Chacoan room that measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. It is located in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. Room 4 has two subunits, 4A to the north and 4B to the south, with 4W referring to the entire room. </desc>
    <unit id="004W">
      <desc>Room 4W was subdivided during the San Juan occupation. The stratigraphic sequence identified in the room contained 15 strata, including structured trash, roof-fall, occupational fill, and two floor surfaces. Lower strata in the room were clearly of Chacoan age, but the upper four strata were mixed, with ceramics from both the Chacoan and San Juan occupations. Three features, including two doors, were in Room 4W. Based on the masonry style and construction techniques in evidence, Room 4W was built during the same interval as the rest of the pueblo from 1090–1100.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="004A">
      <desc>Room 4A measures 2.9 x 2.5 m. Seven stratigraphic units were identified in the room including post-occupational fill layers and a floor sequence from the San Juan era. Six features were associated with Room 4A, including storage pit, a burial with associated artifacts, and a doorway.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="004B">
      <desc>Room 4B measures 3.3 x 2.9 m. Four stratigraphic units were identified in the room including two post-occupational layers and a floor sequence associated with the San Juan occupation. Room 4B has three associated features -- two are door-related and one was a seed cache containing burned corn and ash. The room was used for storage and food preparation. Other uses could have included living or sleeping. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="005">
    <desc>Room 5 is a large rectangular room (Room 5W) in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo that contains a kiva (Room 5A). Room 5W refers to the original Chacoan square room, which measures 5.8 x 4.4 m. The western Chacoan wall, at one point, extended farther east; this wall was removed when the San Juan kiva (Room 5A) was constructed. Five Chacoan strata were defined for Room 5W including a floor surface, occupational level, and feature fill. Room 5W had a single feature, an oval, clay-lined hearth. Room 5W was impacted by pot-hunting activities. It is estimated that Room 5W was built around 5–10 years after the initial construction period at Salmon Pueblo, by 1095.</desc>
    <unit id="005W">
      <desc>Room 5W refers to the original Chacoan square room, which measures 5.8 x 4.4 m. The western Chacoan wall, at one point, extended farther east; this wall was removed when the San Juan kiva (Room 5A) was constructed. Five Chacoan strata were defined for Room 5W including a floor surface, occupational level, and feature fill. Room 5W had a single feature, an oval, clay-lined hearth. Room 5W was impacted by pot-hunting activities. It is estimated that Room 5W was built around 5–10 years after the initial construction period at Salmon Pueblo, by 1095</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="005A">
      <desc>Room 5A is the San Juan period kiva that measures 3.6 m in diameter. The walls were built with sandstone slabs of approximately equal size set in mortar. Eight strata were identified during excavation of the kiva including post-occupational fill units: structured trash, a floor, and a feature stratum associated with the hearth. Twenty features were identified in the kiva including six pilasters, an encircling bench, a southern recess, ventilator shaft, deflector, a hearth, and niche set into the kiva wall.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="006">
    <desc>Room 6W is a big, square, single-story Chacoan room in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. Later during the San Juan period, a kiva (6A) was built into the room. The Chacoan room measures 6.2 x 5.8 m and was the central living room for the room suite including Rooms 3, 4, and 7. The room had a doorway in its west wall that provided access into Room 4W. Twelve stratigraphic units were identified during excavation of 6W including a structured trash deposit, a floor contact surface on top of a decayed floor, and a number of feature-specific deposits. No roof-fall layer was found, probably because the room was converted into a kiva (6A) by the later occupants. Nine features were identified in the room including the west wall doorway, three hearths, several postholes, a storage pit, and a trash pit. The room’s location (plaza facing), its large size, and the hearth and storage features all indicate a predominant living or habitation function. The room was built by the Chacoans during the initial construction of Salmon Pueblo from 1090 to 1094 and was used until the end of the Chacoan period, around 1125.</desc>
    <unit id="006W">
      <desc>Room 6W is a big, square, single-story Chacoan room in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. Later during the San Juan period, a kiva (6A) was built into the room. The Chacoan room measures 6.2 x 5.8 m and was the central living room for the room suite including Rooms 3, 4, and 7. The room had a doorway in its west wall that provided access into Room 4W. Twelve stratigraphic units were identified during excavation of 6W including a structured trash deposit, a floor contact surface on top of a decayed floor, and a number of feature-specific deposits. No roof-fall layer was found, probably because the room was converted into a kiva (6A) by the later occupants. Nine features were identified in the room including the west wall doorway, three hearths, several postholes, a storage pit, and a trash pit. The room’s location (plaza facing), its large size, and the hearth and storage features all indicate a predominant living or habitation function. The room was built by the Chacoans during the initial construction of Salmon Pueblo from 1090 to 1094 and was used until the end of the Chacoan period, around 1125.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="006A">
      <desc>Room 6A is a round kiva structure built into Chacoan Room 6W after 1125. It has a diameter of 4.7 m. Twelve stratigraphic units were identified, including post-occupational fill units, structured trash, a roof-fall layer and a floor unit. Fourteen features were associated with 6A including pilasters, a central hearth and deflector, a sipapu, encircling bench, a wall niche, a southern recess, and a above-floor ventilation tunnel. Based on the masonry style and the ceramics present, the room was built by the San Juan occupants during the late 1100s or early 1200s and was probably used until the end of the occupation in the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="007">
    <desc>Room 7W is located in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and is composed of two smaller rooms:  the southern 3A and the northern 7A. The 7W designation refers to the original Chacoan room and measures 4.8 x 2.5 m. It was subdivided during the San Juan era by a wall made of cobbles set in mortar.</desc>
    <unit id="007W">
      <desc>Room 7W is located in the southwest sector of Salmon Pueblo and is composed of two smaller rooms:  the southern 3A and the northern 7A. The 7W designation refers to the original Chacoan room and measures 4.8 x 2.5 m. It was subdivided during the San Juan era by a wall made of cobbles set in mortar. Seven strata were identified in Room 7W including Chacoan and mixed layers. The Chacoan strata included roof-fall and a well-defined floor unit. Two features were identified, including a doorway in the north-south Chacoan wall leading to Room 4W. The lack of floor features and the position of the room suggest that 7W was used for storage. Architectural attributes and ceramic assemblage indicate construction in 1090-1094.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="007A">
      <desc>Room 7A measures 2.9 x 2.5 m and is the northern half of the divided room. Four strata were defined 7A including fill units, a roof-fall layer, and a floor surface. Three features were identified in the room, with two latillas from construction of the San Juan roof, a piece of matting, and the doorway in the dividing wall. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="003A">
      <desc>Room 3A measures 2.9 x 2.4 m and is the southern half of the divided room (7W). Five strata were defined for 3A including three of San Juan affiliation and two fill strata dating after the San Juan occupation. Most strata showed evidence of disturbance, most likely from pot hunters. Two features were identified in the room, including a doorway leading into Room 7A and a section of collapsed first-floor roof. The room burned at some point during the San Juan occupation, the floor was resurfaced, and the room used again.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="008">
    <desc>Room 8A is an unusual five-sided room in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, constructed during the San Juan period. It measures 2.3 m north-south by of 2m east-west. It is bounded on the west by Room 10W, on the southwest by Room 11W, and on the east by a curved wall. Eight distinct strata were identified in the room. roof-contact layer, cultural fill was more abundant with ceramics, lithics, bone, charcoal, and wood-impressed adobe from the ceiling and roof of the room. The next stratum was an occupational layer that contained some cultural materials and charcoal. The floor contact and floor itself revealed several artifacts in situ, all on the eastern side of the room. No features were associated with Room 8A. The walls showed evidence of burning, but the scant roof-fall layer found was not burned, nor were any deposits on or near the floor. Based on the ceramic types and architectural traits, Room 8A was built between 1200-1250, during the San Juan period.</desc>
    <unit id="008A">
      <desc>Room 8A is an unusual five-sided room in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, constructed during the San Juan period. It measures 2.3 m north-south by of 2m east-west. It is bounded on the west by Room 10W, on the southwest by Room 11W, and on the east by a curved wall. Eight distinct strata were identified in the room. roof-contact layer, cultural fill was more abundant with ceramics, lithics, bone, charcoal, and wood-impressed adobe from the ceiling and roof of the room. The next stratum was an occupational layer that contained some cultural materials and charcoal. The floor contact and floor itself revealed several artifacts in situ, all on the eastern side of the room. No features were associated with Room 8A. The walls showed evidence of burning, but the scant roof-fall layer found was not burned, nor were any deposits on or near the floor. Based on the ceramic types and architectural traits, Room 8A was built between 1200-1250, during the San Juan period.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="009">
    <desc>Room 9W is a poorly defined space in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, built during the San Juan period. It only has one identifiable wall on the south side of the room and its dimensions are unclear. Only one hearth feature was identified. Four stratigraphic units were defined, with one probable floor. The room is tentatively dated as a late San Juan construction (1200 to 1250) of unknown function and was probably associated with Room 8A.</desc>
    <unit id="009W">
      <desc>Room 9W is a poorly defined space in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, built during the San Juan period. It only has one identifiable wall on the south side of the room and its dimensions are unclear. Only one hearth feature was identified. Four stratigraphic units were defined, with one probable floor. The room is tentatively dated as a late San Juan construction (1200 to 1250) of unknown function and was probably associated with Room 8A.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="010">
    <desc>Room 10W is a round, partially exposed structure located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It was built during the San Juan period at Salmon and has an estimated diameter of 5m. Room 10W was probably a kiva. No strata or features were identified. The structure underlies Rooms 8, 9, and 11. Based on the position of the room, it probably dates to the early San Juan period of occupation, between 1120 and 1200.</desc>
    <unit id="010W">
      <desc>Room 10W is a round, partially exposed structure located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It was built during the San Juan period at Salmon and has an estimated diameter of 5m. Room 10W was probably a kiva. No strata or features were identified. The structure underlies Rooms 8, 9, and 11. Based on the position of the room, it probably dates to the early San Juan period of occupation, between 1120 and 1200.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="011">
    <desc>Room 11W is shaped like a parallelogram, is located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, and was built during the San Juan period. It measures 3.5m east-west by 1.9m north-south and contains features that suggest a kiva function and use. The walls were built in a San Juan style with cobbles in adobe mortar. The roof burned, apparently at or near abandonment, and the floor also showed evidence of burning. Nine strata were defined in Room 11W. The roof-fall layer contained trash that may have been on the roof at collapse or deposited post-occupation. The roof-fall stratum contained charcoal and adobe casts of latillas, but no intact wood or charcoal suitable for tree-ring dating. The floor contained a sizeable assemblage including ceramics, lithics, bone, corn, and charcoal. Six features were associated with Room 11W including a hearth and deflector combination and a burial. Based on the ceramic assemblage and its position above Room 10W, Room 11W was probably constructed between 1200-1250.</desc>
    <unit id="011W">
      <desc>Room 11W is shaped like a parallelogram, is located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo, and was built during the San Juan period. It measures 3.5m east-west by 1.9m north-south and contains features that suggest a kiva function and use. The walls were built in a San Juan style with cobbles in adobe mortar. The roof burned, apparently at or near abandonment, and the floor also showed evidence of burning. Nine strata were defined in Room 11W. The roof-fall layer contained trash that may have been on the roof at collapse or deposited post-occupation. The roof-fall stratum contained charcoal and adobe casts of latillas, but no intact wood or charcoal suitable for tree-ring dating. The floor contained a sizeable assemblage including ceramics, lithics, bone, corn, and charcoal. Six features were associated with Room 11W including a hearth and deflector combination and a burial. Based on the ceramic assemblage and its position above Room 10W, Room 11W was probably constructed between 1200-1250.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="012">
    <desc>Room 12W is located in the west section of Salmon Pueblo and was built during the San Juan period. Projected dimensions for the room are 2 x 1.5 m. This room was minimally defined and only one wall was clearly identified. No strata or features were recorded for this unit and there are no images or documents available about it.</desc>
    <unit id="012W">
      <desc>Room 12W is located in the west section of Salmon Pueblo and was built during the San Juan period. Projected dimensions for the room are 2 x 1.5 m. This room was minimally defined and only one wall was clearly identified. No strata or features were recorded for this unit and there are no images or documents available about it. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="013">
    <desc>Room 13W is a small San Juan period room located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2 x 1.4m and lies north of and is associated with Room 14W. Room 13W has a doorway in the east wall opening to an undefined and unexcavated room. The walls were built during the San Juan era with cobbles set in adobe mortar. Four stratigraphic deposits were identified. After the removal of modern sediments, a deteriorated floor was encountered. The limited floor contact assemblage included some Mesa Verde sherds. No features were found in the room. A moderate trash-filled deposit found below the floor level dates to the early San Juan or Chacoan era at the site; no additional work was completed below the trash stratum. Based upon the ceramic assemblage and its high position in the stratigraphy, Room 13W was probably constructed around 1200-1250.</desc>
    <unit id="013W">
      <desc>Room 13W is a small San Juan period room located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2 x 1.4m and lies north of and is associated with Room 14W. Room 13W has a doorway in the east wall opening to an undefined and unexcavated room. The walls were built during the San Juan era with cobbles set in adobe mortar. Four stratigraphic deposits were identified. After the removal of modern sediments, a deteriorated floor was encountered. The limited floor contact assemblage included some Mesa Verde sherds. No features were found in the room. A moderate trash-filled deposit found below the floor level dates to the early San Juan or Chacoan era at the site; no additional work was completed below the trash stratum. Based upon the ceramic assemblage and its high position in the stratigraphy, Room 13W was probably constructed around 1200-1250. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="014">
    <desc>Room 14W is a small San Juan room located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.8 x 2.8 m and lies south of and is associated with Room 13W. The walls were built during the San Juan period with cobbles set in adobe mortar and contain fine sandstone walls on the west and south sides. The walls and floor of 14W were burned during some point of the occupation. Room 14W was cleaned out and reused a second time after the burning. Only one feature, a niche, was found in the room. Six stratigraphic units were defined. Several interesting bone artifacts were found: an awl, a bone scraper, and five long tubular bone beads. The floor of Room 14W did not have any artifacts and was cleaned after the fire. Based on the ceramic assemblage and stratigraphic position, Room 14W was probably constructed in the 1200-1250 interval. </desc>
    <unit id="014W">
      <desc>Room 14W is a small San Juan room located in the west sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.8 x 2.8 m and lies south of and is associated with Room 13W. The walls were built during the San Juan period with cobbles set in adobe mortar and contain fine sandstone walls on the west and south sides. The walls and floor of 14W were burned during some point of the occupation. Room 14W was cleaned out and reused a second time after the burning. Only one feature, a niche, was found in the room. Six stratigraphic units were defined. Several interesting bone artifacts were found: an awl, a bone scraper, and five long tubular bone beads. The floor of Room 14W did not have any artifacts and was cleaned after the fire. Based on the ceramic assemblage and stratigraphic position, Room 14W was probably constructed in the 1200-1250 interval. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="015">
    <desc>Room 15W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo.  It measures 2.9 x 14.5 m. Only limited work was conducted and two strata were defined for the room. There are no feature, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="015W">
      <desc>Room 15W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo.  It measures 2.9 x 14.5 m. Only limited work was conducted and two strata were defined for the room. There are no feature, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="016">
    <desc>Room 16W is located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo. Very limited work was completed and the room dimensions are unclear. Two strata were defined for the room. There are no feature, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="016W">
      <desc>Room 16W is located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo. Very limited work was completed and the room dimensions are unclear. Two strata were defined for the room. There are no feature, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="017">
    <desc>Room 17W is located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo. Very limited work was completed and room dimensions are unclear. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="017W">
      <desc>Room 17W is located in the northwest corner of Salmon Pueblo. Very limited work was completed and room dimensions are unclear. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="030">
    <desc>Room 30W is an original Chacoan room that was later subdivided into two smaller rooms: 30A (east half) and 30B (west half). Room 30W is located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 5.8 m east-west and 2.9 m north-south. </desc>
    <unit id="030W">
      <desc>Room 30W is an original Chacoan room that was later subdivided into two smaller rooms: 30A (east half) and 30B (west half). Room 30W is located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 5.8 m east-west and 2.9 m north-south. Twenty-eight stratigraphic units were defined in Room 30W, including two floor units, one Chacoan, and one of uncertain age; two roof-fall deposits, several distinct layers of structured trash, feature specific strata, and a number of artificial fill and construction debris at lower depths. Most of these strata are Chacoan in age but several are mixed, and the three most recent deposits in Room 30W are from the San Juan period. Nine features were identified in Room 30W, including two Chacoan doorways in the north and south walls of the room, one vent window, and a hearth beneath the Chacoan floor. The south doorway was sealed around the end of the Chacoan occupation of the pueblo, after 1125. The floor was also covered with burned corn and a burned roof. This fire was widespread in the pueblo and occurred in the late 1100s or early 1200s. A north-south cobble wall dividing the room into two smaller rooms—30A and 30B—was built after the fire.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="030A">
      <desc>Room 30A measures 3 x 2.9 m and is identical to 30B in architecture. Six strata were defined including post-occupational units, roof fall, and a floor unit. Room 30A featured two burned floors. Three features were found in Room 30A, including a milling bin, a storage bin, and a wall separating Rooms 30A and 30B. No door was found between these rooms and entrance probably came through a rooftop hatch. Room 30A functioned as milling room to process corn. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="030B">
      <desc>Room 30B measures 3 x 2.9 m and is identical to room 30A in architecture. Six stratigraphic units were identified including post-occupational deposits, roof-fall, and a floor unit. Two features were found including the subdividing wall and a niche cut into the south Chacoan wall. Room 30B was used to store corn before it was milled in adjoining Room 30A. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="030Z">
      <desc>The Room 30Z was defined to represent a hypothetical occupation underneath and before the main Chaco occupation in Room 30W. It is not well documented or confirmed. No features were identified in the room space. Only one stratum - J-1-1 -  was defined. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="031">
    <desc>Room 31W is an original Chacoan room that was later subdivided into two smaller rooms: 31A (east half) and 31B (west half). Room 31W is located directly east of Room 30W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 3.8 by 2.9 m. It lies south of and is connected to Room 43W by a sealed doorway. </desc>
    <unit id="031W">
      <desc>Room 31W is an original Chacoan room that was later subdivided into two smaller rooms: 31A (east half) and 31B (west half). Room 31W is located directly east of Room 30W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 3.8 by 2.9 m. It lies south of and is connected to Room 43W by a sealed doorway. Room 31W contained 30 individual strata including Chacoan and San Juan floor complexes, roof-fall, structured trash, wall and wall-fill units, and feature-related strata. The Chacoan occupation floor in the room contained a number of large lithic core tools, faunal remains, and ceramics. The assemblage suggests that faunal processing and butchering took place in the room. Twenty-six features were identified in Room 31W including Chacoan doorways on the north and south, roofing-related features such as vigas, latillas, and other beams, two San Juan burials, several pits for storage and trash deposition, and two hearths. One burial was located beneath the San Juan occupational floor. The room was used for storage and as a trash zone during the Chacoan period. The first fire in the room probably happened around 1190–1210. The second fire was part of the closing event at the pueblo, in the mid 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="031A">
      <desc>Room 31A is the eastern portion of Room 31W and is in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.9 x 2.5 m. Thirteen strata were identified in 31A including two floors, roof-fall, wall strata, and post-occupational fill. No trash layers were found. Seven features are associated with Room 31A; several were milling bins with slab metates set into mortar with slab masonry borders. Room 31A functioned as a milling room during at least the later period of the San Juan occupation.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="031B">
      <desc>Room 31B is the western portion of Room 31W. it measures 2.9 x 2.5. Twelve strata were identified in 31B including post-occupational units, roof-fall, and a floor. The most recent stratum, the floor complex, revealed evidence of the fire that destroyed Salmon Pueblo. Five features were associated with Room 31B, including a San Juan period wall dividing 31B from 31A.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="032">
    <desc>Room 32W is located directly south of Room 30W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (identified as 32W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva that (Room 32A) was emplaced into the Chacoan room. The Chacoan room measures 5.8 by 2.9 m east-west and the San Juan kiva (Room 32A) has a diameter of 3.3 m. Rubble was cleared from the upper room walls for mapping purposes but very little excavation was completed in the room. No features were identified during limited work in the room. Three strata (B and C types) were defined.</desc>
    <unit id="032W">
      <desc>Room 32W is located directly south of Room 30W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (identified as 32W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva that (Room 32A) was emplaced into the Chacoan room. The Chacoan room measures 5.8 by 2.9 m east-west and the San Juan kiva (Room 32A) has a diameter of 3.3 m. Rubble was cleared from the upper room walls for mapping purposes but very little excavation was completed in the room. No features were identified during limited work in the room. Three strata (B and C types) were defined.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="032A">
      <desc>Room 32A is a round kiva structure built into Chacoan Room 32W after 1125. The San Juan kiva (Room 32A) has a diameter of 3.3 m. Rubble was cleared from the upper room walls for mapping purposes but very little excavation was completed in the room. No features were identified during limited work in the room. Three strata (B and C types) were defined.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="033">
    <desc>Room 33W is located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. It was built during the Chacoan era and modified by adding a kiva (Room 33C) on the second story level during the San Juan occupation. The emplacement of the Room 33C kiva into Room 33W created two other smaller room spaces 33A and 33B. </desc>
    <unit id="033W">
      <desc>Room 33W is located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. It was built during the Chacoan era and modified by adding a kiva (Room 33C) on the second story level during the San Juan occupation. The emplacement of the Room 33C kiva into Room 33W created two other smaller room spaces 33A and 33B. Twenty-two strata were found in Room 33W. Most were Chacoan in origin with the upper two from the San Juan occupation. Twenty-four features were associated with Room 33W. These include Chacoan vent windows, doorways, three lithic concentrations, Chacoan-age hearths, the remains of a macaw, and a burial. Later work between Rooms 33W and 42W revealed the presence of two additional macaws in the doorway between the rooms. Room 33W contained two small carved stone effigies. Tree ring dates indicate Room 33W was built during the initial construction phase at Salmon in 1090, with some repairs occurring around 1103.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="033A">
      <desc>Room 33A is a small space on the east side of 33W formed when the kiva (Room 33C) was added to Room 33W. It measures 2.9 x 0.9 m. Six strata were identified in Room 33A including a floor, roof-fall, post-occupational fill, and a trash layer. No features were identified. Given the room’s unusual size and shape, it is unclear how occupants used the room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="033B">
      <desc>Room 33B is a small space located to the west of the kiva (Room 33C) in the northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.9 x 2.1 m. Thirteen strata were identified including two floor complexes, two layers of roof-fall, post-occupational layers, trash deposits, and feature-specific strata. Four features were identified in Room 33B: two latillas from the burned roof and two burials with several individuals. Given the room’s unusual size and shape, it is unclear how occupants used the room beyond its use as a burial chamber.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="033C">
      <desc>Room 33C is the San Juan period kiva in 33W. It measures 2.5 m in diameter and was added to the second-story floor of Room 33W. It was not centered, but offset by 1m to the west. Thirteen strata were identified in 33C: two floor units, two layers of roof-fall, trash deposits, and post-occupational fill.Nineteen features were associated with the 33C kiva: eight distinct plaster layers on the wall, a ventilator shaft, a cobble-lined hearth, a niche, a viga and latilla from the burned roof, and a mural. The mural depicted two anthropomorphic figures and an anthropomorphic design. The Roo 33C kiva is lacking some typical kiva features, such as pilasters, a bench, and a deflector. The ceramic assemblage and stratigraphy indicate that the kiva was used between 1170-1290.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="034">
    <desc>The Room 34W designation was originally used for a room that later had its number changed. Thus, Room 34W is not used in the SPARC archive.</desc>
    <unit id="034W">
      <desc>The Room 34W designation was originally used for a room that later had its number changed. Thus, Room 34W is not used in the SPARC archive.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="035">
    <desc>Room 35W is located directly south of Room 31W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (identified as Room 35W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva that (Room 35A) was emplaced into the Chacoan room. </desc>
    <unit id="035W">
      <desc>Room 35W is located directly south of Room 31W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (identified as Room 35W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva that (Room 35A) was emplaced into the Chacoan room. The Chacoan room measures 5.8 by 3.6 m east-west and the San Juan kiva has a diameter of 3.3 m. Rubble was cleared from the upper room walls for mapping purposes but very little excavation was completed in the room. One hearth feature was identified and three strata (B and C types) were defined for the room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="035A">
      <desc>Room 35A is the San Juan period kiva in 35W. It measures 3.3 m in diameter. Rubble was cleared from the upper room walls for mapping purposes but very little excavation was completed in the room. One hearth feature was identified and three strata (B and C types) were defined for the room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="036">
    <desc>Room 36W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. Unlike other rooms in this sector of the pueblo, Room 36W was never divided. Room 36W had 46 strata, most attributed to the San Juan occupation. Strata included a San Juan age floor, roof-fall, multiple trash units, post-occupational fill, and feature-related deposits. Thirty-six features were recorded in Room 36W including vigas, latillas, or sockets for roofing, vent windows, doors, an ash pit, wall niches, and lithic concentrations. Tree-ring dates from Room 36W indicate construction and remodeling from 1089-1105. This combined with ceramic and stratigraphic data indicates that the room was used until the terminal fire of the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="036W">
      <desc>Room 36W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. Unlike other rooms in this sector of the pueblo, Room 36W was never divided. Room 36W had 46 strata, most attributed to the San Juan occupation. Strata included a San Juan age floor, roof-fall, multiple trash units, post-occupational fill, and feature-related deposits. Thirty-six features were recorded in Room 36W including vigas, latillas, or sockets for roofing, vent windows, doors, an ash pit, wall niches, and lithic concentrations. Tree-ring dates from Room 36W indicate construction and remodeling from 1089-1105. This combined with ceramic and stratigraphic data indicates that the room was used until the terminal fire of the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="037">
    <desc>Room 37W is the next room directly east of Room 36W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. Room 37W was subdivided during the San Juan era creating two smaller rooms: 37A on the east and 37B on the west. </desc>
    <unit id="037W">
      <desc>Room 37W is the next room directly east of Room 36W in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The original Chacoan room measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. Room 37W was subdivided during the San Juan era creating two smaller rooms: 37A on the east and 37B on the west. Thirty-three stratigraphic units were identified in room 37W including floor deposits, two roof-fall layers, several trash layers, feature-related deposits, and deposits related to construction of the room. A burned roof was found above the Chacoan floor unit. This might be attributed to the fire that burned most of the western sector of Salmon pueblo in the 1190s. Thirty-four features were recorded in Room 37W. Four vent windows, two doors, three hearths, and an ash pit were associated with the Chacoan occupation. San Juan era features included three pits,and a large storage pit. Tree ring dates from Room 37W indicate construction of the room around 1090. It was used until the mid to late 1100s and the dividing wall (creating Rooms 37A and B) was constructed in the 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="037A">
      <desc>Room 37A measures 2.9 x 2.5 m. The east wall and floor were painted with a red hematite-based paint during the San Juan occupation. Twelve strata were identified in Room 37A: two floor complexes, a burned roof-fall layer, two trash deposits, and post-occupational fill were found. Seven features were found in 37A including a hearth, two niches, the wall dividing 37A and 37B, and the painted floor and wall.  The hearth and lower room remains indicate a habitation function for Room 37A. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="037B">
      <desc>Room 37B measures 2.9 x 2.9 m. Six strata were associated with 37B: two post-occupational fill layers, a structured trash layer, a roof-fall deposit, and a floor complex. Only one feature was identified in Room 37B: a burial with the remains of an infant and a 3-5 year old child. The near absence of features in Room 37B suggests a storage function.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="037Z">
      <desc>Room 37Z was defined to represent a hypothetical occupation before the main Chacoan occupation, which was not well documented or confirmed.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="038">
    <desc>Room 38W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, several meters northwest of Room 64W (Tower Kiva). It measures 5 x 2.9 m. A doorway is the only feature identified for the room. Ten ceramic artifacts were recovered from this room but there are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available.</desc>
    <unit id="038W">
      <desc>Room 38W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, several meters northwest of Room 64W (Tower Kiva). It measures 5 x 2.9 m. A doorway is the only feature identified for the room. Ten ceramic artifacts were recovered from this room but there are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="039">
    <desc>Room 39W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5 x 2.2 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="039W">
      <desc>Room 39W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5 x 2.2 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="040">
    <desc>Room 40W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. A doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="040W">
      <desc>Room 40W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. A doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="041">
    <desc>Room 41W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 2.2 m. A doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="041W">
      <desc>Room 41W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 2.2 m. A doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="042">
    <desc>Room 42W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.5 m. Two macaws were found in 2006 in a collapsed doorway between Room 42W and 33W (to the north). In addition, a doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. Beyond this find, there are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="042W">
      <desc>Room 42W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.5 m. Two macaws were found in 2006 in a collapsed doorway between Room 42W and 33W (to the north). In addition, a doorway feature was identified, as well as two strata. Beyond this find, there are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="043">
    <desc>Room 43W is an original Chacoan room located on the back row of rooms in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 2.5 m and was not structurally modified in the San Juan period. It lies north of and is connected to Room 31W by a sealed doorway. In all, 29 strata were designated in Room 43W. The upper strata relate to the San Juan occupation. These include several fill layers, feature deposits associated with burials, and several layers of roof-fall. The remaining strata date to the Chacoan era. These included a floor unit, occupational and trash layers, and construction debris. Thirty-one features were associated with Room 43W: vigas, latillas, Chacoan doorways, a wooden feature (identified as a drying rack for food), a wood curtain, two pits, and burials. There was also a dense concentration of lithics with many unmodified sandstone fragments and quartzite cobbles. Tree ring dates indicate initial construction of 43W during the Chacoan era, around 1090. Given the stratigraphy, 43W seems to have seen activity throughout the San Juan period throughout the mid-1100s to the mid to late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="043W">
      <desc>Room 43W is an original Chacoan room located on the back row of rooms in the northwest sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 2.5 m and was not structurally modified in the San Juan period. It lies north of and is connected to Room 31W by a sealed doorway. In all, 29 strata were designated in Room 43W. The upper strata relate to the San Juan occupation. These include several fill layers, feature deposits associated with burials, and several layers of roof-fall. The remaining strata date to the Chacoan era. These included a floor unit, occupational and trash layers, and construction debris. Thirty-one features were associated with Room 43W: vigas, latillas, Chacoan doorways, a wooden feature (identified as a drying rack for food), a wood curtain, two pits, and burials. There was also a dense concentration of lithics with many unmodified sandstone fragments and quartzite cobbles. Tree ring dates indicate initial construction of 43W during the Chacoan era, around 1090. Given the stratigraphy, 43W seems to have seen activity throughout the San Juan period throughout the mid-1100s to the mid to late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="044">
    <desc>Room 44W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 2.5 m. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="044W">
      <desc>Room 44W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 2.5 m. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="045">
    <desc>Room 45W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 3.3 m. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="045W">
      <desc>Room 45W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 3.3 m. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="046">
    <desc>Room 46W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 5.5 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="046W">
      <desc>Room 46W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.2 x 5.5 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="047">
    <desc>Room 47W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. Little work was completed and the room size is unclear. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="047W">
      <desc>Room 47W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. Little work was completed and the room size is unclear. One doorway feature was defined along with two strata. No photographic or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="048">
    <desc>Room 48W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 4.7 x 2.9 m. Two doorway features were defined along with a single stratum.There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="048W">
      <desc>Room 48W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 4.7 x 2.9 m. Two doorway features were defined along with a single stratum.There are no photographic or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="051">
    <desc>Room 51W is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It is an original Chacoan room that was not structurally modified during the San Juan period. It measures 5.4 m x 3.2 m. Forty-five strata were identified in 51W. The upper strata are from the San Juan occupation of Salmon Pueblo and include two floor surfaces, two roof-fall layers, post-occupational fill, structured trash, and feature-related deposits. The six Chacoan strata are subfloor deposits, including wall foundations and artificial fill used for construction. Eleven features were identified in Room 51W. The Chacoan features included doorways in the north and south walls and the underlying foundation, whereas the San Juan era features consisted of two postholes. The function and use of the room is unclear. Based on the evidence, Room 51W was not heavily used in either period. Tree ring dates indicate construction in the initial Salmon construction phase at 1090. The room was continuously used throughout both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="051W">
      <desc>Room 51W is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It is an original Chacoan room that was not structurally modified during the San Juan period. It measures 5.4 m x 3.2 m. Forty-five strata were identified in 51W. The upper strata are from the San Juan occupation of Salmon Pueblo and include two floor surfaces, two roof-fall layers, post-occupational fill, structured trash, and feature-related deposits. The six Chacoan strata are subfloor deposits, including wall foundations and artificial fill used for construction. Eleven features were identified in Room 51W. The Chacoan features included doorways in the north and south walls and the underlying foundation, whereas the San Juan era features consisted of two postholes. The function and use of the room is unclear. Based on the evidence, Room 51W was not heavily used in either period. Tree ring dates indicate construction in the initial Salmon construction phase at 1090. The room was continuously used throughout both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="052">
    <desc>Room 52W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo in front of Room 63W. It measures 5.5 x 2.2 m. No work was conducted in this room and no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available.</desc>
    <unit id="052W">
      <desc>Room 52W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo in front of Room 63W. It measures 5.5 x 2.2 m. No work was conducted in this room and no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="053">
    <desc>Room 53W is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo along the back wall. It is an original Chacoan room that was not structurally modified during the San Juan period. Room 53W measures 5.5 x 2.5 m. Fourteen strata were identified, with the lowest five of Chacoan origin (including artificial fill, construction debris, and a floor unit).  The upper strata were mixed and attributed to both Chacoan and San Juan eras. Fifteen features were identified in 53W, including a Chacoan doorway in the south wall, numerous latilla and beam sockets, a pit, and a lithic concentration. The function and use of this room is unclear;  the sparse feature assemblage strongly suggests a storage function. Tree ring dates indicate construction around 1090, during the initial Chacoan era construction. The room was used in both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="053W">
      <desc>Room 53W is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo along the back wall. It is an original Chacoan room that was not structurally modified during the San Juan period. Room 53W measures 5.5 x 2.5 m. Fourteen strata were identified, with the lowest five of Chacoan origin (including artificial fill, construction debris, and a floor unit).  The upper strata were mixed and attributed to both Chacoan and San Juan eras. Fifteen features were identified in 53W, including a Chacoan doorway in the south wall, numerous latilla and beam sockets, a pit, and a lithic concentration. The function and use of this room is unclear;  the sparse feature assemblage strongly suggests a storage function. Tree ring dates indicate construction around 1090, during the initial Chacoan era construction. The room was used in both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="054">
    <desc>Room 54W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo along the back wall. Room 54W measures 5.8 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  but two tree-ring dates (at 1088 v v) were obtained from wood samples. There are no feature, strata, photographic, and few documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="054W">
      <desc>Room 54W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo along the back wall. Room 54W measures 5.8 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  but two tree-ring dates (at 1088 v v) were obtained from wood samples. There are no feature, strata, photographic, and few documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="055">
    <desc>Room 55W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. Room 55W measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="055W">
      <desc>Room 55W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo. Room 55W measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="056">
    <desc>Room 56W is an original, square Chacoan room east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.7 x 6 m. Eleven strata were associated with 56W, including a Chacoan floor, roof-fall, feature fill, and trash deposits. Twenty-five features were found in 56W, mostly relating to construction or roofing activities. Other features included Chacoan doorways and hearths. Room 56W is located at the front of a suite of connected rooms and probably served as the primary living space in the suite. Tree-ring dates indicate construction during the initial period of Chacoan construction at Salmon Pueblo, around 1090.</desc>
    <unit id="056W">
      <desc>Room 56W is an original, square Chacoan room east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.7 x 6 m. Eleven strata were associated with 56W, including a Chacoan floor, roof-fall, feature fill, and trash deposits. Twenty-five features were found in 56W, mostly relating to construction or roofing activities. Other features included Chacoan doorways and hearths. Room 56W is located at the front of a suite of connected rooms and probably served as the primary living space in the suite. Tree-ring dates indicate construction during the initial period of Chacoan construction at Salmon Pueblo, around 1090.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="057">
    <desc>Room 57W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W).  It measures 5.5 x 3.2 m. Twenty strata were identified in Room 57W. The upper strata were San Juan era in origin, consisting of roof-fall layers. The middle strata were mixed roof-fall strata with Chacoan and San Juan ceramics. The lowest strata were fill units with Chacoan ceramics and construction materials. Few artifacts were recovered from any of the strata in 57W. Sixty-four features were identified in Room 57W, the majority being latillas, vigas, and their respective wall sockets. Other features included doorways, a niche, five hearths, and a ladder made of stone. This ladder construction is unique to Salmon Pueblo, and provided access to a second-story doorway into Room 58W. Room 57W probably served a habitation or living function.</desc>
    <unit id="057W">
      <desc>Room 57W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W).  It measures 5.5 x 3.2 m. Twenty strata were identified in Room 57W. The upper strata were San Juan era in origin, consisting of roof-fall layers. The middle strata were mixed roof-fall strata with Chacoan and San Juan ceramics. The lowest strata were fill units with Chacoan ceramics and construction materials. Few artifacts were recovered from any of the strata in 57W. Sixty-four features were identified in Room 57W, the majority being latillas, vigas, and their respective wall sockets. Other features included doorways, a niche, five hearths, and a ladder made of stone. This ladder construction is unique to Salmon Pueblo, and provided access to a second-story doorway into Room 58W. Room 57W probably served a habitation or living function.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="058">
    <desc>Room 58W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Eighteen strata were identified in Room 58W, one post-occupational stratum, eleven units with mixed Chacoan and San Juan ceramics, three Chacoan age strata, and a pre-Chacoan stratum. Twenty features were identified in 58W, more than 10 related to the roof or roofing materials and were probably used during the Chacoan occupation. Other features included three Chacoan doorways, two vent windows, a Chacoan hearth, a San Juan era floor pit, and a burial in a roof-fall layer. The San Juan era use of the room involved two floors. The earlier Chacoan floor produced limited ceramics and a basket while the later floor had a pit feature and very few ceramics. Based on the evidence, Room 58W is inferred to be a storage space. A singular tree ring date indicates construction around 1090, during the initial Chacoan era construction. The room was continuously used throughout both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="058W">
      <desc>Room 58W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Eighteen strata were identified in Room 58W, one post-occupational stratum, eleven units with mixed Chacoan and San Juan ceramics, three Chacoan age strata, and a pre-Chacoan stratum. Twenty features were identified in 58W, more than 10 related to the roof or roofing materials and were probably used during the Chacoan occupation. Other features included three Chacoan doorways, two vent windows, a Chacoan hearth, a San Juan era floor pit, and a burial in a roof-fall layer. The San Juan era use of the room involved two floors. The earlier Chacoan floor produced limited ceramics and a basket while the later floor had a pit feature and very few ceramics. Based on the evidence, Room 58W is inferred to be a storage space. A singular tree ring date indicates construction around 1090, during the initial Chacoan era construction. The room was continuously used throughout both occupations into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="059">
    <desc>Room 59W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.5 m north-south x 5.4 m east-west. It is connected to Rooms 38W and 62W through doorways. It was partially excavated during the Salmon Project. Twenty strata were identified in 59W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, structured trash, feature-specific layers, and two floor complexes. All excavated strata are associated with the San Juan era. Eighteen features were identified in Room 59W. Ten appear to be of Chacoan origin, including  three doorways, several latilla and viga sockets, a niche, two other wall features, and a unique red sandstone mosaic inferred to be of archaeo-astronomical importance. The San Juan era features included two hearths, postholes, wall plaster, a ramada-esque feature, and two lithic concentrations. The uses of this room are unclear based on the partial excavation. It is unknown what the Chacoan use was but it my have been used for residential purposes during the San Juan era. Given the location of 59W and tree-ring dates from adjacent rooms in this area, it was built in the 1090s and used into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="059W">
      <desc>Room 59W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.5 m north-south x 5.4 m east-west. It is connected to Rooms 38W and 62W through doorways. It was partially excavated during the Salmon Project. Twenty strata were identified in 59W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, structured trash, feature-specific layers, and two floor complexes. All excavated strata are associated with the San Juan era. Eighteen features were identified in Room 59W. Ten appear to be of Chacoan origin, including  three doorways, several latilla and viga sockets, a niche, two other wall features, and a unique red sandstone mosaic inferred to be of archaeo-astronomical importance. The San Juan era features included two hearths, postholes, wall plaster, a ramada-esque feature, and two lithic concentrations. The uses of this room are unclear based on the partial excavation. It is unknown what the Chacoan use was but it my have been used for residential purposes during the San Juan era. Given the location of 59W and tree-ring dates from adjacent rooms in this area, it was built in the 1090s and used into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="060">
    <desc>Room 60W is an original Chacoan room located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.5 x 2 m. Room 60W was subdivided creating two smaller rooms: 60A to the east and 60B to the west. Excavation proceeded with these two rooms but stopped before reaching the strata below the dividing wall.Tree ring dates suggest construction around 1090 and it is estimated that Room 60A was used into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="060W">
      <desc>Room 60W is an original Chacoan room located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 6.5 x 2 m. Room 60W was subdivided creating two smaller rooms: 60A to the east and 60B to the west. Excavation proceeded with these two rooms but stopped before reaching the strata below the dividing wall. No strata or features were assigned to 60W. The Chacoan use of 60W is unclear. Tree ring dates suggest construction around 1090 and it is estimated that Room 60A was used into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="060A">
      <desc>Room 60A was created when Room 60W was subdivided in the Early San Juan period. It measures 2.75 m east-west by 2 m north-south. Thirteen strata were identified: six roof-fall units that comprised an almost intact roof, an occupational unit, and several fill strata. No floor was found probably because excavations did not reach the deeper levels in Room 60A. Five features were identified, including a mostly intact roof comprised of adobe, vigas, latillas, juniper bark, and small wood elements. The relative lack of features in Room 60A suggests a storage function.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="060B">
      <desc>Room 60B was created when Room 60W was subdivided in the Early San Juan period. It measures 4.5 m east-west by 2 m north-south. Most excavation records for this room are in poor condition or missing. The wall and floor were painted with a red hematite. Twenty-three strata were identified in 60B, mostly dating to the San Juan era. A few wall based units were of the Chacoan period. Upper strata included a trash deposit, fill units, roof-fall, two floors, and feature-specific units. The upper floor articulates with the San Juan wall separating 60A from 60B. The lower floor could be either Chacoan or San Juan age. Since many of the excavation notes are missing, the total number of features is unknown. Fourteen features are known in 60B. These include a Chacoan doorway, three San Juan era hearths, several walls, and construction related features. The hearths indicate that Room 60B was used for a living function in the San Juan occupation.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="061">
    <desc>Rooms 61A and 61B are interstitial support rooms located south-southwest of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W).</desc>
    <unit id="061A">
      <desc>Room 61A is an interstitial support room located south-southwest of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It is a triangular-shaped room and measures 3.6 east-west by 2.1 m north-south. Five strata were identified in 61A: two post-occupational fill layers and three Chacoan artificial fill strata. Twenty features were identified -- all were vigas or other construction beams to support the Tower Kiva. Room 61A was used as a support space for the Tower Kiva complex and held up one of the latter’s buttresses. Tree ring dates indicate construction during the initial Chacoan era, around 1090.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="061B">
      <desc>Room 61B is an interstitial support room located south-southwest of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It is a triangular room measuring 2.1 m east-west by 5.7 m north-south. Five Chacoan period strata were identified. Fifteen features were associated with Room 61B, most were support beams relating to the room’s primary support function. Room 61B was used as a support space for the Tower kiva complex and held up one of the buttresses supporting the kiva.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="062">
    <desc>Room 62W is an original Chacoan room and is the largest at Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the central section of the pueblo and measures 7.5 x 5.8 m. It was connected to Room 68W to the south and 59W to the north with doorways. Room 62W is separated from 62A by strata - Room 62A comprises the upper 13 strata. Since it was located directly west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64), many artifacts were preserved in excellent condition. A few of these artifacts include food remains, perishables, and coprolites. </desc>
    <unit id="062W">
      <desc>Room 62W is an original Chacoan room and is the largest at Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the central section of the pueblo and measures 7.5 x 5.8 m. It was connected to Room 68W to the south and 59W to the north with doorways. Room 62W is separated from 62A by strata - Room 62A comprises the upper 13 strata. Since it was located directly west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64), many artifacts were preserved in excellent condition. A few of these artifacts include food remains, perishables, and coprolites. A total of 121 strata was identified in Room 62W, including many trash deposits, occupational fill, feature fill, construction debris and fill, and several floors. Most of the trash deposits in 62W were from the San Juan occupation, indicating that it was mostly used as an in-site midden in the last 100 years or so of its uselife. Fifty-five features were identified in Room 62W. Many were associated with construction activities: vigas, latillas, sockets, posts, and wall plaster. Numerous Chacoan period features were identified including wall niches, doorways, pits, hearths, and trash deposits. Room 62W was initially occupied during the Chacoan era, perhaps for living purposes. The evidence supports a domestic function rather than ceremonial, despite the close proximity to the Tower Kiva. During the San Juan occupation, 62W was used as a trash deposit, latrine, and possibly as a depository for ritual and perishable items that were no longer needed. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="062A">
      <desc>Room 62A is designated as the upper 13 strata in Room 62. All strata were from the San Juan era and included a floor complex, roof-fall, an occupational deposit, layers of feature fill, and post-occupational fill. Room 62A also contained 19 features, some relating to roof construction, along with hearths, ash pits, a sandstone seat, and two wall segments. These wall segments subdivided 62 and defined Room 62B (used as a turkey pen). One of the hearths was from the second story floor that collapsed with the roof. No tree ring dates were obtained specifically from the post-Chacoan use of the room. However, the stratigraphy and ceramic assemblage in Room 62A indicate use from the mid-1100s to late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="062B">
      <desc>Room 62B is a small, subdivided room portion in the southwest corner of Room 62W. The area measures 2 x 1.3 m, with walls at a height of 0.55 m. One stratum was identified in Room 62B, a roof-fall layer from the 62A roof. No features were recorded. Room 62B served as a turkey pen in the San Juan period.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="064">
    <desc>Room 64W is the central Tower Kiva at Salmon Pueblo, constructed during the initial Chacoan period around 1090 and used until the 1280s. It is located in the center of Salmon’s east-west trending main roomblock. The Tower Kiva measures 8.5 m in diameter at the bench level and 7 m at floor level. The bench, which is 0.75 m wide, encircles the entire kiva. Although this structure is Chacoan in origin, most of the actual deposits recovered from it reflect San Juan reuse over 150 years after the end of the Chacoan period.  </desc>
    <unit id="064W">
      <desc>Room 64W is the central Tower Kiva at Salmon Pueblo, constructed during the initial Chacoan period around 1090 and used until the 1280s. It is located in the center of Salmon’s east-west trending main roomblock. The Tower Kiva measures 8.5 m in diameter at the bench level and 7 m at floor level. The bench, which is 0.75 m wide, encircles the entire kiva. Although this structure is Chacoan in origin, most of the actual deposits recovered from it reflect San Juan reuse over 150 years after the end of the Chacoan period.  The Tower Kiva was constructed on a platform 3 m in height, to raise the floor to the second-story level of the surrounding pueblo rooms. Of the 28 strata defined in the Tower Kiva, 19 relate to the San Juan occupation, including the Kiva floor. Other strata include occupational fill, roof-fall, and feature related strata. Chacoan strata were identified in the eastern floor vault (foot drum), which was apparently never used by the San Juan occupants. Eight Chacoan strata were defined. A Chacoan floor was identified but no features were present. In all, 76 features were recorded in the Tower Kiva. Most related to construction - postholes, vigas, beams, or sockets. The list of Chacoan features reused by the San Juan occupants included the central hearth, deflector, western floor vault (foot drum), bench, pilasters, walls, and the original roofing material. Several layers of plaster were identified, including part of a San Juan kiva mural in white paint. During the San Juan occupation, The structure had a subfloor ventilation shaft large enough for a person to crawl through. Four buttresses constructed during the initial Chacoan use surround the kiva structure, located between the outer wall of the kiva and the encircling walls in adjacent rooms. The remaining features relate to the architecture, to ritual, or to other activities inside the kiva. Ritual features included a sand-filled sipapu and two floor vaults, or foot drums, on the east and west sides of the kiva floor. The eastern floor vault contained a number of significant artifacts and remains. Yellow ochre was scattered across its floor, along with a tchamahia, fragments of wooden artifacts, and numerous ceramics. Next to the floor vault were some juniper planks cut to fit the feature; they were 2–3 cm thick and up to 30 cm wide. Many artifacts were found in the kiva, including a carved stone effigy of a female lizard effigy of sandstone, whole ceramic vessels, burned ceramics and basketry, carved stone beads, a cloth bag, a leather pouch, and sandals. An intentional fire (and cremation event) at end of the San Juan occupation ended use of the structure. The heat of the fire twas so intense in localized areas that some artifacts were completely burned, and ceramic vessels were vitrified. In other areas, the fire was less intense, and served to dry out and preserve perishable remains. Thus, numerous botanical items were recovered in situ on the structure’s San Juan age floor: corn, beans with pods still attached, prickly pear pads, cholla buds, piñon nuts, and a large piece of squash. The nature of these items indicates that the fire took place in the fall, shortly after harvest time. Tree-ring dates indicate that the structure was built during Salmon’s first construction episode at 1090 and used throughout the San Juan occupation to the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="065">
    <desc>Room 65W is an original Chacoan period plaza-facing room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5 x 2.2m. Room 65W had a doorway in its north wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="065W">
      <desc>Room 65W is an original Chacoan period plaza-facing room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5 x 2.2m. Room 65W had a doorway in its north wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="066">
    <desc>Room 66W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just north of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W).  It measures 5 x 2.9m. Room 66W had a doorway in its east wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="066W">
      <desc>Room 66W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just north of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W).  It measures 5 x 2.9m. Room 66W had a doorway in its east wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="067">
    <desc>Room 67W is an original Chacoan room located behind the Tower Kiva (Room 64W), in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.3 x 2.9 m. It was built during the Chacoan occupation around 1090. Twenty-five strata were identified in 67W including mixed Chacoan and San Juan layers, several roof fall layers, post-occupational fill, structured trash, feature-specific strata, and a floor. In all, 35 features were found in 67W. Features included    vigas and latillas, doorways, vent windows, and a pit. Tree ring dates indicate construction of 67W around 1090, during the Chacoan era. The lack of floor features suggests a storage function for this room. Stratigraphic data and ceramic frequencies suggest continued usage into the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="067W">
      <desc>Room 67W is an original Chacoan room located behind the Tower Kiva (Room 64W), in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.3 x 2.9 m. It was built during the Chacoan occupation around 1090. Twenty-five strata were identified in 67W including mixed Chacoan and San Juan layers, several roof fall layers, post-occupational fill, structured trash, feature-specific strata, and a floor. In all, 35 features were found in 67W. Features included    vigas and latillas, doorways, vent windows, and a pit. Tree ring dates indicate construction of 67W around 1090, during the Chacoan era. The lack of floor features suggests a storage function for this room. Stratigraphic data and ceramic frequencies suggest continued usage into the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="068">
    <desc>Room 68W is an original Chacoan period plaza-facing room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just southwest of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.5 x 1.8 m. Room 68W had a single feature - a viga near its north wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="068W">
      <desc>Room 68W is an original Chacoan period plaza-facing room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just southwest of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.5 x 1.8 m. Room 68W had a single feature - a viga near its north wall. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no strata were defined. There are no strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="069">
    <desc>Room 69W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5 x 2.2 m.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="069W">
      <desc>Room 69W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5 x 2.2 m.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="070">
    <desc>Room 70W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 7.3 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls . One doorway feature was recorded on the south side of the room. No strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="070W">
      <desc>Room 69W is an original Chacoan room located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5 x 2.2 m.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="071">
    <desc>Room 71W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north-northwest of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="071W">
      <desc>Room 71W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north-northwest of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="072">
    <desc>Room 72W is an original Chacoan interstitial room located north of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="072W">
      <desc>Room 72W is an original Chacoan interstitial room located north of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="073">
    <desc>Room 73W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="073W">
      <desc>Room 73W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and is located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="074">
    <desc>Room 74W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north-northeast of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W). No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="074W">
      <desc>Room 74W is an original Chacoan interstitial support room located north-northeast of Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W). No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="075">
    <desc>Room 75W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="075W">
      <desc>Room 75W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="076">
    <desc>Room 76W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.5 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls . A doorway on the room’s south side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="076W">
      <desc>Room 76W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.5 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls . A doorway on the room’s south side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="077">
    <desc>Room 77W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2. A doorway on the room’s south side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="077W">
      <desc>Room 77W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2. A doorway on the room’s south side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="078">
    <desc>Room 78W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.5. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="078W">
      <desc>Room 78W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, along the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.5. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="079">
    <desc>Room 79W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, in the 2nd tier of rooms from the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.9. A doorway on the room’s east side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="079W">
      <desc>Room 79W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, in the 2nd tier of rooms from the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.9. A doorway on the room’s east side is the only feature identified and no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="080">
    <desc>Room 80W is located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, south of Room 79W.  It measures 5.6 x 3.6. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="080W">
      <desc>Room 80W is located in the central portion of Salmon Pueblo, south of Room 79W.  It measures 5.6 x 3.6. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="081">
    <desc>Room 81W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and measures 5.3 x 2.5 m. Sixteen strata were identified in 81W. Below two post-occupational layers were structured trash and roof-fall strata of San Juan age; next were structured trash and roof-fall of mixed San Juan and Chacoan affiliation. The lowest units were Chacoan in age, including a floor with very few associated remains. Twelve features were associated with 81W, including latillas and sockets of either Chacoan or San Juan origin and Chacoan doorways. One of the features contained posts forming some sort of rack feature with many unique lithic artifacts. Room 81W was built during the initial construction period, around 1090 and used by people during both periods until the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="081W">
      <desc>Room 81W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and measures 5.3 x 2.5 m. Sixteen strata were identified in 81W. Below two post-occupational layers were structured trash and roof-fall strata of San Juan age; next were structured trash and roof-fall of mixed San Juan and Chacoan affiliation. The lowest units were Chacoan in age, including a floor with very few associated remains. Twelve features were associated with 81W, including latillas and sockets of either Chacoan or San Juan origin and Chacoan doorways. One of the features contained posts forming some sort of rack feature with many unique lithic artifacts. Room 81W was built during the initial construction period, around 1090 and used by people during both periods until the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="082">
    <desc>Room 82W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 4.9 x 2.4 m. A post and adobe wall divided the structure, producing a small room space on the west side, designated Room 82A. Much of what is known about Room 82W indicates a specialized, ritual function for the room. The room’s complicated deposits resulted in the recording of 78 strata and 65 features.</desc>
    <unit id="082W">
      <desc>Room 82W is an original Chacoan room located in the central section of Salmon Pueblo, just east of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 4.9 x 2.4 m. A post and adobe wall divided the structure, producing a small room space on the west side, designated Room 82A. Much of what is known about Room 82W indicates a specialized, ritual function for the room. The room’s complicated deposits resulted in the recording of 78 strata and 65 features. The upper 16 strata are linked to the San Juan occupation at Salmon. These include a floor complex, several roof-fall layers, structured trash, and feature-related strata. Chacoan strata began with a series of roof-fall deposits over structured trash and occupational deposits and finally ended with a series of floor surfaces separated by artificial fill. The 65 features recorded in Room 82W represent both the Chacoan and San Juan eras. Many of the Chacoan features were construction-related, including lintels for the doors and vigas and latillas from the roof. Numerous Chacoan features related to living or residence were also identified, including hearths, heating pits, a bin, a slab feature, and several pits of unknown function. One archaeo-astronomical feature, inferred to have been important for ceremonial activity including the observation of the sky, was found. San Juan occupation features included a broad mix of functions, some of which were related to construction. Other features suggest residence in the room: hearths and two discrete burials were put into the room after its primary use was finished. Other interesting features included a post structure interpreted as a drying rack, an adobe and wood platform built against the east wall, and a series of three posts interpreted as loom posts. Tree ring dates indicate initial construction around 1090, during the initial construction episode. The room was used into the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="082A">
      <desc>Room 82A comprises the western two-thirds of Room 82W. It measures 3.3 x 2.4 m. The dividing wall was built during the Chacoan era as a room partition. Four Chacoan age strata were found, including a floor surface, feature strata, and artificial fill layers. Four features were found, including hearths and lithic concentrations. These features indicate a residential or living function.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="083">
    <desc>Room 83W is an original Chacoan room located in the back tier of rooms along Salmon’s north wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m and was built during the earliest occupation at Salmon, about  1090. Twelve strata were identified in 83W, including post-occupational fill at the top, San Juan era strata following, and mixed Chacoan and San Juan era layers. The lowest (Chacoan) layers included a floor and a wall foundation. A total of 19 features was associated with Room 83W, most linked to the Chacoan occupation. These features consisted of vigas, the south wall doorway and intel, vent windows in the north wall, and a pit of unknown function.</desc>
    <unit id="083W">
      <desc>Room 83W is an original Chacoan room located in the back tier of rooms along Salmon’s north wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m and was built during the earliest occupation at Salmon, about  1090. Twelve strata were identified in 83W, including post-occupational fill at the top, San Juan era strata following, and mixed Chacoan and San Juan era layers. The lowest (Chacoan) layers included a floor and a wall foundation. A total of 19 features was associated with Room 83W, most linked to the Chacoan occupation. These features consisted of vigas, the south wall doorway and intel, vent windows in the north wall, and a pit of unknown function.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="084">
    <desc>Room 84W is an original Chacoan room located in the second tier of rooms from Salmon’s north wall. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Fourteen strata were identified in the room, including a mix of Chacoan and San Juan deposits. One San Juan period roof-fall strata was recorded. The remaining deposits in the room were of Chacoan origin, including a floor, trash and occupational layers, feature specific strata, and a number of strata related to the room’s construction. Eight features were associated with Rooms 84W including doorways in the north and south walls, vent windows, a storage pit and a trash pit. Given these findings and the room’s location, a storage function seems likely. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090.</desc>
    <unit id="084W">
      <desc>Room 84W is an original Chacoan room located in the second tier of rooms from Salmon’s north wall. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Fourteen strata were identified in the room, including a mix of Chacoan and San Juan deposits. One San Juan period roof-fall strata was recorded. The remaining deposits in the room were of Chacoan origin, including a floor, trash and occupational layers, feature specific strata, and a number of strata related to the room’s construction. Eight features were associated with Rooms 84W including doorways in the north and south walls, vent windows, a storage pit and a trash pit. Given these findings and the room’s location, a storage function seems likely. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="085">
    <desc>Room 85W is an original Chacoan room located in the east section of the north block of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. The room was modified by the later San Juan occupants, with a dividing wall creating two room spaces (Rooms 85A and 85B). The room was excavated for about a week in 1974. Work was terminated when the unstable north wall created a dangerous situation. Four strata were associated with the room, all recorded in Room 85W, 85A, and 85B. These included post-occupational fill, roof-fall, and fill strata. Three features were identified in the room; doorways in the north, west, and south walls. Based on its location and architecture, Room 85W was part of the initial construction episode at Salmon in 1090.</desc>
    <unit id="085W">
      <desc>Room 85W is an original Chacoan room located in the east section of the north block of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. The room was modified by the later San Juan occupants, with a dividing wall creating two room spaces (Rooms 85A and 85B). The room was excavated for about a week in 1974. Work was terminated when the unstable north wall created a dangerous situation. Four strata were associated with the room, all recorded in Room 85W, 85A, and 85B. These included post-occupational fill, roof-fall, and fill strata. Three features were identified in the room; doorways in the north, west, and south walls. Based on its location and architecture, Room 85W was part of the initial construction episode at Salmon in 1090.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="086">
    <desc>Room 86W is an original Chacoan large square room located in the eastern portion of Salmon’s main room block. It measures 5.7 x 5.7 m. It was built during the initial construction episode (around 1090) and later modified with kiva-like features by the San Juan occupants. Sixty-three strata were recorded in 86W, most relating to the San Juan occupation. Many of the strata were feature-related; there were also multiple San Juan and Chacoan floors. Roof fall and trash deposit layers were also found. Most of the 111 features found in 86W related to the San Juan era modifications turning the room into a kiva structure. These include post holes, hearths, a ventilator shaft, several niches, pits, a milling bin, and four burials. Chacoan features included doorways, hearths, post holes, and more than a dozen pits of unknown use. The original Chacoan room probably functioned as a living or residential room.San Juan modification of the room resulted in its conversion to a kiva-like structure. No tree ring dates were obtained, but the room’s location, stratigraphy, and Chacoan assemblages suggests construction during the initial episode, around 1090 and used by San Juan period people until the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="086W">
      <desc>Room 86W is an original Chacoan large square room located in the eastern portion of Salmon’s main room block. It measures 5.7 x 5.7 m. It was built during the initial construction episode (around 1090) and later modified with kiva-like features by the San Juan occupants. Sixty-three strata were recorded in 86W, most relating to the San Juan occupation. Many of the strata were feature-related; there were also multiple San Juan and Chacoan floors. Roof fall and trash deposit layers were also found. Most of the 111 features found in 86W related to the San Juan era modifications turning the room into a kiva structure. These include post holes, hearths, a ventilator shaft, several niches, pits, a milling bin, and four burials. Chacoan features included doorways, hearths, post holes, and more than a dozen pits of unknown use. The original Chacoan room probably functioned as a living or residential room.San Juan modification of the room resulted in its conversion to a kiva-like structure. No tree ring dates were obtained, but the room’s location, stratigraphy, and Chacoan assemblages suggests construction during the initial episode, around 1090 and used by San Juan period people until the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="087">
    <desc>Room 87W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, in the 2nd tier of rooms from the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.9. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features were defined. Only one strata was designated. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="087W">
      <desc>Room 87W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo, in the 2nd tier of rooms from the back wall. It measures 5.8 x 2.9. No work was completed beyond exposing walls  and no features were defined. Only one strata was designated. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="088">
    <desc>Room 88W was built during the San Juan period and was originally thought to be a completely enclosed structure. Further investigation indicated that it was an extramural, partially enclosed plaza workspace. The area had enclosing walls from adjacent complete rooms on the north and east and an expedient partial wall on top of San Juan deposits on the west but no wall on the south. The space enclosed by the wall measured 3.6 x 3.3 m. Ten strata were identified in 8W including post-occupational fill, structured trash, feature fill, and floor and floor contact layers. Three features were defined in the room including two burials and a San Juan era subdividing wall. The room space and function are not clear. Given the ceramic assemblage, Room 88W was probably built late in the occupation of Salmon, after 1200.</desc>
    <unit id="088W">
      <desc>Room 88W was built during the San Juan period and was originally thought to be a completely enclosed structure. Further investigation indicated that it was an extramural, partially enclosed plaza workspace. The area had enclosing walls from adjacent complete rooms on the north and east and an expedient partial wall on top of San Juan deposits on the west but no wall on the south. The space enclosed by the wall measured 3.6 x 3.3 m. Ten strata were identified in 8W including post-occupational fill, structured trash, feature fill, and floor and floor contact layers. Three features were defined in the room including two burials and a San Juan era subdividing wall. The room space and function are not clear. Given the ceramic assemblage, Room 88W was probably built late in the occupation of Salmon, after 1200.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="089">
    <desc>Room 89W is an original Chacoan room located along Salmon’s back wall in the northeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. Nine strata were identified in Room 89W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, unstructured San Juan trash fill, occupational fill, and a floor. A mix of Chacoan and San Juan ceramics was found under the floors. Eight features were identified in 89W, including a Chacoan doorway in the south wall, upright posts, and four vent windows located in the upper east and west portions of the north and south walls. The windows were sealed at some point during the occupation. Its location along the back wall and the absence of floor features indicate a probable storage function during both periods of occupation. Upright posts were installed on either side of the Chacoan door during the San Juan occupation to make the room easier to seal off as a storage facility. Given its location and assemblage, Room 89W was built during the initial occupation, around 1090. Later San Juan use of the room continued from the mid-1100s into the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="089W">
      <desc>Room 89W is an original Chacoan room located along Salmon’s back wall in the northeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. Nine strata were identified in Room 89W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, unstructured San Juan trash fill, occupational fill, and a floor. A mix of Chacoan and San Juan ceramics was found under the floors. Eight features were identified in 89W, including a Chacoan doorway in the south wall, upright posts, and four vent windows located in the upper east and west portions of the north and south walls. The windows were sealed at some point during the occupation. Its location along the back wall and the absence of floor features indicate a probable storage function during both periods of occupation. Upright posts were installed on either side of the Chacoan door during the San Juan occupation to make the room easier to seal off as a storage facility. Given its location and assemblage, Room 89W was built during the initial occupation, around 1090. Later San Juan use of the room continued from the mid-1100s into the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="090">
    <desc>Room 90W is located directly south of Room 89W, in the northeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room was originally built during the Chacoan construction episode around 1090, with perhaps some repairs or upper-story construction at 1094. A total of 26 strata was identified in Room 90W, including post-occupational fill, structured trash, roof-fall, occupational fill, floor and floor contact debris, artificial fill, construction debris, and feature fill. There was a mixed Chacoan and San Juan trash deposit separating the two periods of use. Thirty-three features were associated with Room 90W. Chacoan features included three doorways (in the west, north, and south walls), vent windows, a hearth, three pits of unknown purpose, and a large series of vigas from the roof. San Juan features include a burial and an adobe-lined pit. The location of 90W in the second to last tier of rooms at Salmon suggests that it served primarily as a storage room but the presence of a hearth feature may signal some habitation use. Tree-ring dates from Room 90W indicate initial construction during the 1090 episode by the Chacoans. The room was probably used by San Juan residents until the 1280s. </desc>
    <unit id="090W">
      <desc>Room 90W is located directly south of Room 89W, in the northeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room was originally built during the Chacoan construction episode around 1090, with perhaps some repairs or upper-story construction at 1094. A total of 26 strata was identified in Room 90W, including post-occupational fill, structured trash, roof-fall, occupational fill, floor and floor contact debris, artificial fill, construction debris, and feature fill. There was a mixed Chacoan and San Juan trash deposit separating the two periods of use. Thirty-three features were associated with Room 90W. Chacoan features included three doorways (in the west, north, and south walls), vent windows, a hearth, three pits of unknown purpose, and a large series of vigas from the roof. San Juan features include a burial and an adobe-lined pit. The location of 90W in the second to last tier of rooms at Salmon suggests that it served primarily as a storage room but the presence of a hearth feature may signal some habitation use. Tree-ring dates from Room 90W indicate initial construction during the 1090 episode by the Chacoans. The room was probably used by San Juan residents until the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="091">
    <desc>Room 91W is an original Chacoan room located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. The room was built during the initial Chacoan construction episode around 1090 and subsequently modified by the San Juan occupants. This later activity resulted in the creation of three room spaces (91A, B, and C). The 91D designation was used across the Room 91W area for a series of strata that were believed to be San Juan in origin. </desc>
    <unit id="091W">
      <desc>Room 91W is an original Chacoan room located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. The room was built during the initial Chacoan construction episode around 1090 and subsequently modified by the San Juan occupants. This later activity resulted in the creation of three room spaces (91A, B, and C). The 91D designation was used across the Room 91W area for a series of strata that were believed to be San Juan in origin. However, this use occurred below the San Juan dividing wall so it properly belongs to the original Chacoan Room 91W (but was not recorded that way). Of the 40 strata recorded in Room 91W, most were related to trash mounds that accrued in the room over time as refused was put into the room. Other strata include post-occupational units, floor units, and construction related fill. Room 91W contained 8 features including four doorways, two vent windows, a macaw, and one recorded latilla beam. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090 and the ceramic assemblage indicates use into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="091A">
      <desc>Room 91A is the middle San Juan period room (between 91C and B) created when 91W was divided. The room has an L shape, with maximum dimensions of 3.6 m north-south by 3.6 m east-west. Nineteen strata were identified in 91A  including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, trash deposits, and upper and lower floors. Four features were recorded including two hearths, a milling bin, and a doorstep associated with the door connecting Rooms 91A and 91C. Based on the features present, Room 91A  was used as a milling and habitation room, and for trash deposition subsequently. Ceramic data indicate usage into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="091B">
      <desc>Room 91B is a small San Juan period storage room built into the corner of 91W. The room measures 1.5 x 1.5 m and was apparently constructed as a storage area for Room 85B. Nineteen strata were recorded in Room 91B. Seven of these relate to various components of the walls used to enclose the room. Four strata define consecutive roof-fall units from the collapse of the structure’s roof. Trash strata were defined along with other occupational fill units and a floor. One storage pit feature was recorded. The room probably functioned as a small storeroom for the adjoining Room 85B. Based on the ceramic assemblage, construction and use occurred between the mid-1100s and 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="091C">
      <desc>Room 91C is the western third of the subdivided Room 91W that measures 3.6 x 1.8 m. The room was created and used between the mid-1100s and the late 1200s by the San Juan occupants. Nine strata were defined in Room 91C, including post-occupational layers, roof-fall, and floor units. A metate, a mano, other ground stone, and lithic artifacts were associated with the floor unit. Six features were recorded in the room including four narrow wall slots, a door step, and a wall niche. Based on architecture, stratigraphy, and ceramic assemblage, construction and use occurred between the mid 1100s and late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="091D">
      <desc>Room 91D was used to designate post-Chacoan strata beneath the San Juan Rooms 91A–C, across the entire area of original Chacoan Room 91W. This approach was unique in the work at Salmon Pueblo and resulted in duplication of strata and floor surfaces across these room units. The strata and features grouped under the Room 91D designation properly belong with Room 91W. Thirteen strata were identified in 91D  including two floors, artificial fill, and structured trash units. A metate and ceramic vessel were found on the floor layer. The ceramic assemblage from these deposits is mixed, including Chacoan-age ceramics and later 12th and 13th century types such as Mesa Verde Black-on-white. Room 91D had two cobble features on the floor surface.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="092">
    <desc>Room 92W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central part of the main room block of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 5.8 m. It contains multiple subrooms 92 A-F that were created in the post-Chacoan San Juan period.</desc>
    <unit id="092W">
      <desc>Room 92W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central part of the main room block of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.8 x 5.8 m. It contains multiple subrooms 92 A-F that were created in the post-Chacoan San Juan period. Room 92W contained 34 strata including four defined floor complexe within about 15 cm. It seems improbable that all represent discrete occupations and more likely that one or two reworked floors were in use. Below the reworked floor surfaces were artificial fill strata, feature-fill, and two eroded surfaces, and preconstruction deposits. Thirty-four features were associated with 92W and are Chacoan in origin. These features include three doorways, hearths, storage pits, a floor vault, a series of floor slots, vigas, latillas, and postholes. The feature assemblage indicates that 92W was used as a residential room by the Chacoans. Tree ring dates indicate construction around 1090. Occupation continued through the Chacoan period into the 1120s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092A">
      <desc>Room 92A is the San Juan period kiva emplaced in Chacoan Room 92W in the post-Chacoan period. The structure measures 4.4 m in diameter and its construction created interstitial spaces (92B–F) around it between the kiva and room walls. Seventeen strata were identified in the 92A kiva including trash and a floor layer. Sixteen features were associated with the kiva, many of which are typical of San Juan kiva features. These included a central hearth, deflector, ventilator shaft and tunnel, a southern recess, and a round structural wall. In contrast, the kiva lacks features found in other kivas at the site, such as pilasters, a bench, and a sipapu. Architecture and ceramics indicate construction in the late mid-1100s or early 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092B">
      <desc>Room 92B is a small interstitial space that measures 2.9 x 0.95 m and is located in the southeastern portion of Room 92W between the room and kiva walls. Only two strata were defined for 92B. The only feature was a burial. Considerable trash was found in the space and it appears to have functioned largely as a support area for the 92A kiva. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092C">
      <desc>Room 92C is an interstitial space between the 92A kiva and the eastern Chacoan wall of 92W. It was created with construction of the kiva by the San Juan occupants of Salmon. The space measures 5.5 x 2.3 m. In all, 12 strata were identified in this room including a floor complex and other strata. Seven features were found in 92C including a sealed doorway, two wall niches, and four adobe plugs in the east wall. The doorway indicates that 92C was used to access the 92A kiva. Thus, 92C apparently served an antechamber-like purpose.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092D">
      <desc>Room 92D is the northwest interstitial space next to the kiva in 92A. Three strata were defined for the room but no features were recorded and it was not excavated. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092E">
      <desc>Room 92E is the southwest interstitial space next to the 92A kiva. Four strata were defined for the room but no features were recorded and it was not excavated. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="092F">
      <desc>Room 92F is an extremely small interstitial space located between the 92A kiva and 92B. No strata or features were defined and the space was not excavated. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="093">
    <desc>Room 93W is an original Chacoan room and part of what has been called Salmon’s gallery, located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.2 x 2.9 m. The room was one of the most intensively used at Salmon, with seven distinct floors (four Chacoan and three San Juan). The room was not structurally modified by the later San Juan inhabitants, who used the room for perhaps 150 years from the mid-1100s into the 1280s. A total of 88 strata were identified in Room 93W. San Juan age strata included trash, roof-fall, occupational fill, and three distinct floor surfaces. Chacoan strata included artificial fill, wall foundations, structural debris below the earliest floor, feature fill, roof-fall, and four floor complexes. Forty-six features were identified in 93W with the majority relating to the Chacoan occupation: hearths, bell-shaped storage pits, subfloor storage cists, wall niches, an ash pit, and several pits of unknown use. Other features included four doorways, a wall extension, and postholes. These features indicate a residential-living use for the room during the Chacoan period. San Juan features were fewer in number but also indicated residential usage: hearths, milling bins, storage cists, and a single burial. Room 93W was originally built as an open “gallery” in front of the pueblo facing the plaza. Later, walls were added, and a more typical room structure emerged. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around the initial occupation beginning in 1090. The use of Room 93W was clearly intensive during both the Chacoan period and the later San Juan occupation, with use until the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="093W">
      <desc>Room 93W is an original Chacoan room and part of what has been called Salmon’s gallery, located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 7.2 x 2.9 m. The room was one of the most intensively used at Salmon, with seven distinct floors (four Chacoan and three San Juan). The room was not structurally modified by the later San Juan inhabitants, who used the room for perhaps 150 years from the mid-1100s into the 1280s. A total of 88 strata were identified in Room 93W. San Juan age strata included trash, roof-fall, occupational fill, and three distinct floor surfaces. Chacoan strata included artificial fill, wall foundations, structural debris below the earliest floor, feature fill, roof-fall, and four floor complexes. Forty-six features were identified in 93W with the majority relating to the Chacoan occupation: hearths, bell-shaped storage pits, subfloor storage cists, wall niches, an ash pit, and several pits of unknown use. Other features included four doorways, a wall extension, and postholes. These features indicate a residential-living use for the room during the Chacoan period. San Juan features were fewer in number but also indicated residential usage: hearths, milling bins, storage cists, and a single burial. Room 93W was originally built as an open “gallery” in front of the pueblo facing the plaza. Later, walls were added, and a more typical room structure emerged. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around the initial occupation beginning in 1090. The use of Room 93W was clearly intensive during both the Chacoan period and the later San Juan occupation, with use until the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="094">
    <desc>Room 94W is a  medium-sized San Juan kiva located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo.  It measures 4.2 m in diameter. Thirteen strata were identified in 94W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature-specific strata, and a kiva floor complex. Rooms 94A-C refer to the interstitial spaces between the kiva and the enclosing walls.</desc>
    <unit id="094W">
      <desc>Room 94W is a  medium-sized San Juan kiva located in the central sector of Salmon Pueblo.  It measures 4.2 m in diameter. Thirteen strata were identified in 94W, including post-occupational fill, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature-specific strata, and a kiva floor complex. Rooms 94A-C refer to the interstitial spaces between the kiva and the enclosing walls. The floor contained a suite of features and artifacts. Eight features were associated with 94W including a central hearth, a deflector, a bench, a ventilator system, and wall niches. No tree-ring dates were recovered but the ceramic assemblage reflects usage sometime from the mid 1100s to the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="094A">
      <desc>Room 94A is the northwest interstitial space next to the 94W kiva. This small space, which was filled with trash and rubble during the construction of the kiva, served to stabilize the structure’s wall. Three strata were recorded in the room. No features were identified in 94A.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="094B">
      <desc>Room 94B is small San Juan room space between the enclosing wall for the 94W kiva and Room 88W to the west. This space measures 4 m north-south by 2.4 m east-west. Three strata were defined, including post-occupational fill. Given the limited data, little interpretation of this area is possible beyond its use as a structural support space for the Room 94W kiva.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="094C">
      <desc>Room 94C is the northeast interstitial space next to the 94W kiva. This small space was filled with trash and rubble during the construction of the kiva and served to stabilize the structure’s wall. In addition, a burial was placed into the midden fill. Eight strata were recorded in the room: two post-occupational units, three feature-specific units, and structured trash deposits. Features in the 94C space consisted of a burial, a doorway that originated with Room 102A to the north, and a pit of unknown purpose.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="095">
    <desc>Room 95W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.5 x 3.6 m. No work beyond wall definition was completed in this room. A single doorway feature was noted. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="095W">
      <desc>Room 95W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.5 x 3.6 m. No work beyond wall definition was completed in this room. A single doorway feature was noted. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="096">
    <desc>Room 96W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeastern transect of Salmon Pueblo and measures 5.7 x 5.7 m. Towards the end of the Chacoan occupation, 96W was converted into a kiva. Subsequently, additional San Juan kiva features were added, including a southern recess and pilasters. The designation “96W” is for both the square Chacoan room and the kiva. The names 96A and 96C were applied to the interstitial spaces created when the round kiva was emplaced into the square room. The 96B label was applied to the southern recess of the Room 96A kiva.</desc>
    <unit id="096W">
      <desc>Room 96W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeastern transect of Salmon Pueblo and measures 5.7 x 5.7 m. Towards the end of the Chacoan occupation, 96W was converted into a kiva. Subsequently, additional San Juan kiva features were added, including a southern recess and pilasters. The designation “96W” is for both the square Chacoan room and the kiva. The names 96A and 96C were applied to the interstitial spaces created when the round kiva was emplaced into the square room. The 96B label was applied to the southern recess of the Room 96A kiva. These rooms only produced two strata. Thirty-seven strata, most of Chacoan origin, were identified in 96W. The upper two levels were post-occupational fill, followed by four San Juan age strata: two roof-fall layers and a floor complex for the kiva. Immediately below the kiva floor was another floor complex, presumably Chacoan in origin. The rest of the strata were feature-related deposits. A total of 49 features was identified in Room 96W from both the Chacoan and San Juan periods. Chacoan features included hearths, an ash pit, two adobe-lined pits, two doorways, and more than 10 pits of unknown use. Most of the San Juan age features were directly related to the room’s conversion into a kiva structure later in time, including pilasters, a masonry bench, walls built around the structure above the bench to create a round interior, a ventilator shaft and tunnel, hearth and deflector, and several wall niches. No tree-ring dates were obtained, but given the room’s location, there is little doubt that 96W was built during the initial Chacoan construction around 1090 and used into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="096A">
      <desc>Rooms 96A and 96C were applied to the interstitial spaces created when the round kiva (96W) was emplaced into the square room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="096B">
      <desc>The 96B label was applied to the southern recess of the Room 96A kiva.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="096C">
      <desc>Rooms 96A and 96C were applied to the interstitial spaces created when the round kiva (96W) was emplaced into the square room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="097">
    <desc>Room 97W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon’s main room block. It measures 6 x 3.7 m. In the San Juan period, it was subdivided into Rooms 97A and 97B. Thirty-one strata were identified in 97W, most of Chacoan age. These included three floors, feature-specific deposits, structured trash, artificial fill layers, construction debris, and pre-occupational fill. A total of 31 features was defined, most of Chacoan origin, including doorways, a hearth, a subfloor pit, 12 milling bins in a row, and steps leading to the roof. The San Juan features consisted of two vigas, two burials, and the cobble wall that divides 97A and 97B. The 12 milling bins indicate a primary corn milling function during the Chacoan period. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090, and was used throughout the San Juan occupation into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="097W">
      <desc>Room 97W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon’s main room block. It measures 6 x 3.7 m. In the San Juan period, it was subdivided into Rooms 97A and 97B. Thirty-one strata were identified in 97W, most of Chacoan age. These included three floors, feature-specific deposits, structured trash, artificial fill layers, construction debris, and pre-occupational fill. A total of 31 features was defined, most of Chacoan origin, including doorways, a hearth, a subfloor pit, 12 milling bins in a row, and steps leading to the roof. The San Juan features consisted of two vigas, two burials, and the cobble wall that divides 97A and 97B. The 12 milling bins indicate a primary corn milling function during the Chacoan period. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090, and was used throughout the San Juan occupation into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="097A">
      <desc>Room 97A is the San Juan period western half of the subdivided 97W and measures 3.4 x 2.6 m. Five strata were defined, including a trash deposit and a floor complex. Three burial features were found. Ceramics and stratigraphic data confirm a period of use from the middle 1100s into the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="097B">
      <desc>Room 97B is the San Juan period eastern half of 97W and measures 3.7 x 3.4. The room contained six strata including two post-occupational units, a structured trash layer, and a floor complex. The room is entirely of San Juan affiliation. Five features were recorded, including vigas and latillas from the roof and two burials.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="098">
    <desc>Room 98W is an original Chacoan room located in the second tier of rooms from Salmon’s back wall, in the northeast corner of the pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Ten strata were identified in 98W including a San Juan age roof-fall and fill, a trash deposit, a Chacoan floor complex and occupational level. Twelve features were found in 98W. Two were of Chacoan age and consisted of the doorways located in the north and south walls. All of the San Juan age features related to the roof or roof-fall, including vigas, latillas and a large section of fallen roof. Based on its location and the features found, it is probable that 98W was used for storage. Tree- ring dates indicate that the room was constructed during the initial Chacoan period at 1090 and was later used by the San Juan occupants until the late 1200s. </desc>
    <unit id="098W">
      <desc>Room 98W is an original Chacoan room located in the second tier of rooms from Salmon’s back wall, in the northeast corner of the pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Ten strata were identified in 98W including a San Juan age roof-fall and fill, a trash deposit, a Chacoan floor complex and occupational level. Twelve features were found in 98W. Two were of Chacoan age and consisted of the doorways located in the north and south walls. All of the San Juan age features related to the roof or roof-fall, including vigas, latillas and a large section of fallen roof. Based on its location and the features found, it is probable that 98W was used for storage. Tree- ring dates indicate that the room was constructed during the initial Chacoan period at 1090 and was later used by the San Juan occupants until the late 1200s. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="099">
    <desc>Room 99W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast corner of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.2 x 2.2 m. Much of Salmon’s back two rows of rooms collapsed as a unit at some point after abandonment. Thus, little of the room’s walls were present at the time of excavation and not much accumulated fill was present. Five strata were identified including two post-occupational fill layers and a floor complex. The floor had few artifacts and no features. The only feature was a Chacoan doorway. Given its location, 99W was likely built around 1090 in the initial wave of Chacoan construction.</desc>
    <unit id="099W">
      <desc>Room 99W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast corner of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.2 x 2.2 m. Much of Salmon’s back two rows of rooms collapsed as a unit at some point after abandonment. Thus, little of the room’s walls were present at the time of excavation and not much accumulated fill was present. Five strata were identified including two post-occupational fill layers and a floor complex. The floor had few artifacts and no features. The only feature was a Chacoan doorway. Given its location, 99W was likely built around 1090 in the initial wave of Chacoan construction.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="100">
    <desc>Room 100W is an original Chacoan room and one of the largest rooms in Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the northeastern section of the Pueblo and measures 6.4 x 6.4 m. Unlike many other rooms at the Pueblo, this room was not architecturally modified during the San Juan occupation. At least two Chacoan floors could be defined, which suggests multiple use functions. The original floor shows numerous pits, hearths, post holes, and a corrugated vessel set in the floor. The room was abandoned during Chacoan times and was subsequently used as a major Chacoan and Chacoan-San Juan transition trash repository. A total of 76 strata was found in 100W; most were Chacoan, but several San Juan deposits were encountered, including a roof-fall layer and a structured trash deposit. Below the San Juan deposits were a couple of mixed layers with Chacoan and San Juan sherds. Chacoan strata included structured trash deposits and feature related strata on top of a floor layer. This floor layer contained hundreds of artifacts. Thirty-eight features were associated with 100W, most of Chacoan origin. The two San Juan features were both burials interred late in the occupation. The Chacoan features comprised hearths, two macaw burials, two turkey burials, an ash pit, vent windows, niches, many floor pits, doorways, and one burial. The Chacoan features suggest a primary living function for the room while the San Juan burials and trash deposits indicate dumping refuse and interring the dead. Tree ring dates indicate initial construction around 1090. The strata and features indicate that 100W was continually used throughout the San Juan occupation, into the late 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="0100W">
      <desc>Room 100W is an original Chacoan room and one of the largest rooms in Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the northeastern section of the Pueblo and measures 6.4 x 6.4 m. Unlike many other rooms at the Pueblo, this room was not architecturally modified during the San Juan occupation. At least two Chacoan floors could be defined, which suggests multiple use functions. The original floor shows numerous pits, hearths, post holes, and a corrugated vessel set in the floor. The room was abandoned during Chacoan times and was subsequently used as a major Chacoan and Chacoan-San Juan transition trash repository. A total of 76 strata was found in 100W; most were Chacoan, but several San Juan deposits were encountered, including a roof-fall layer and a structured trash deposit. Below the San Juan deposits were a couple of mixed layers with Chacoan and San Juan sherds. Chacoan strata included structured trash deposits and feature related strata on top of a floor layer. This floor layer contained hundreds of artifacts. Thirty-eight features were associated with 100W, most of Chacoan origin. The two San Juan features were both burials interred late in the occupation. The Chacoan features comprised hearths, two macaw burials, two turkey burials, an ash pit, vent windows, niches, many floor pits, doorways, and one burial. The Chacoan features suggest a primary living function for the room while the San Juan burials and trash deposits indicate dumping refuse and interring the dead. Tree ring dates indicate initial construction around 1090. The strata and features indicate that 100W was continually used throughout the San Juan occupation, into the late 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="101">
    <desc>Room 101W is an original Chacoan room located in the second row of rooms from the back wall in the northeastern section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Eighteen strata were identified in 101W, including post occupational fill and San Juan and Chacoan age deposits. The San Juan era strata consisted of roof-fall, fill, and structured trash. Chacoan strata included a floor complex, occupational fill, structured trash, and feature related deposits. A total of 13 features, all Chacoan in origin, was recorded in Room 101W. Chacoan features consisted of roof-related features, hearths, a slab feature, and a storage pit. These features support the idea that 101W was used for a habitation function. Tree-ring dates indicate that 101W was built during the initial Chacoan occupation around 1090 and subsequently used by the San Juan inhabitants.</desc>
    <unit id="0101W">
      <desc>Room 101W is an original Chacoan room located in the second row of rooms from the back wall in the northeastern section of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.7 x 2.9 m. Eighteen strata were identified in 101W, including post occupational fill and San Juan and Chacoan age deposits. The San Juan era strata consisted of roof-fall, fill, and structured trash. Chacoan strata included a floor complex, occupational fill, structured trash, and feature related deposits. A total of 13 features, all Chacoan in origin, was recorded in Room 101W. Chacoan features consisted of roof-related features, hearths, a slab feature, and a storage pit. These features support the idea that 101W was used for a habitation function. Tree-ring dates indicate that 101W was built during the initial Chacoan occupation around 1090 and subsequently used by the San Juan inhabitants.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="102">
    <desc>Room 102 is a Chacoan gallery room located in the northeastern transect of Salmon Pueblo. The whole room designation 102W was not used because Rooms 102A (west) and 102B (east) were created during the placement of walls. Room 102A was further subdivided in the Chacoan period into two smaller rooms (102C and 102D) with a low adobe wall. Room 102A, after it became a separate room, shows indications of multipurpose food preparation activities, before being used for trash deposition during the Chacoan-San Juan transition and into the San Juan occupation.</desc>
    <unit id="0102A">
      <desc>Room 102A is the western portion of the larger gallery room 102. It measures 4.4 x 3 m. It is the most complicated space in the gallery with 47 defined strata. These strata include San Juan era fill and trash deposits, Chacoan age floor units, trash, fill layers, construction debris, and feature-specific strata. Twenty-nine features were recorded in 102A, from both Chacoan and San Juan occupations. Features from the Chacoan occupation include doorways, several pits, a slab feature, a hearth, a storage pit, a ventilator shaft, and wall niches. The San Juan age features include a concentration of faunal refuse and ceramic assemblage in a wall niche. The hearth and pits suggest a living function after it was subdivided from 102B. No tree ring dates were obtained, but from its location, it was probably built during or shortly after the initial construction, between 1090 and 1100.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="0102B">
      <desc>Room 102B is the larger, eastern half of the subdivided 102; it measures 7.3 x 3 m. Thirteen strata were identified. Below the upper were eight strata of San Juan age: two associated with burial features and the other six of structured trash. Room 102B had five features: a post, a posthole, and three burials. It seems likely that the room was built in the 1090-1100 interval.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="0102C">
      <desc>Room 102C is the western subdivided portion of 102A. As a lower room space below 102A, it has a short stratigraphic sequence. Five strata of Chacoan age were identified: two trash layers, a floor with few artifacts, a feature-based unit, and a wall foundation. Three features were found: a Chacoan pit, wall, and burial of probably San Juan origin. The room’s original function is unclear but it was used as a trash-dumping area in the late Chacoan and San Juan periods.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="0102D">
      <desc>Room 102D is the eastern subdivided portion of 102A. Ten Chacoan strata were identified in the room. No floor was found; the strata consisted of trash deposits, artificial fill layers, and feature-specific strata. Artifacts were found in all strata. Room 102D had four Chacoan age features: three postholes and a pit of unknown function. The room’s original function is unclear but it was used as a trash-dumping area in the late Chacoan and San Juan periods.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="103">
    <desc>Room 103W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 5.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and only one doorway feature was defined in the west wall. No strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0103W">
      <desc>Room 103W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 5.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and only one doorway feature was defined in the west wall. No strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="104">
    <desc>Room 104W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall.  The room measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and only one stratum were defined; no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0104W">
      <desc>Room 104W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall.  The room measures 5.8 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and only one stratum were defined; no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="105">
    <desc>Room 105W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one doorway feature and one stratum were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0105W">
      <desc>Room 105W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 3.6 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one doorway feature and one stratum were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="106">
    <desc>Room 106W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 3.3 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features and two strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0106W">
      <desc>Room 106W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 3.3 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features and two strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="107">
    <desc>Room 107W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 2.5 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features and two strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0107W">
      <desc>Room 107W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 2.5 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features and two strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="108">
    <desc>Room 108W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 2.9 x 2.5m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. One doorway feature and one stratum were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0108W">
      <desc>Room 108W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 2.9 x 2.5m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. One doorway feature and one stratum were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="109">
    <desc>Room 109W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0109W">
      <desc>Room 109W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="117">
    <desc>Room 117W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 2.2 x 1.8 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. One doorway feature was recorded; no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0117W">
      <desc>Room 117W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 2.2 x 1.8 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. One doorway feature was recorded; no strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="118">
    <desc>Room 118W is an original Chacoan room, of small size in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.9 x 2.2 m. Rooms 118W and 119W were the only rooms that could be clearly identified by the excavators in this part of the pueblo as having two stories. Room 118W contained 31 strata, with only two Chacoan or pre-Chacoan deposits. San Juan age deposits, included roof-fall, structured trash, fill units, feature-related strata, and two distinct floor surfaces. The floor had evidence of activities, including corn milling and storage, and a large amount of corn was recovered from the room. Based on the remains, at least a cubic meter of corn was stored in the room, on the second-story floor. Much of the corn burned when a fire went through the room late in the occupation. Forty-two features were identified in Room 118W, only four were of Chacoan age: four doorways. Most of the San Juan features relate to the burned roof and roof-fall (vigas, latillas, sockets). Other features of note included walls built inside the original Chacoan south and west walls, a burial, and a milling bin. During the San Juan occupation, the room was used for corn storage and milling. In addition, two tchamahias and three axes were recovered from the room, suggesting it also served as a repository for ritual items. Tree-ring dates and ceramic evidence indicate initial construction of the room around 1090, with repairs to the roof at 1105, and San Juan use from the mid-1100s to 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="0118W">
      <desc>Room 118W is an original Chacoan room, of small size in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 2.9 x 2.2 m. Rooms 118W and 119W were the only rooms that could be clearly identified by the excavators in this part of the pueblo as having two stories. Room 118W contained 31 strata, with only two Chacoan or pre-Chacoan deposits. San Juan age deposits, included roof-fall, structured trash, fill units, feature-related strata, and two distinct floor surfaces. The floor had evidence of activities, including corn milling and storage, and a large amount of corn was recovered from the room. Based on the remains, at least a cubic meter of corn was stored in the room, on the second-story floor. Much of the corn burned when a fire went through the room late in the occupation. Forty-two features were identified in Room 118W, only four were of Chacoan age: four doorways. Most of the San Juan features relate to the burned roof and roof-fall (vigas, latillas, sockets). Other features of note included walls built inside the original Chacoan south and west walls, a burial, and a milling bin. During the San Juan occupation, the room was used for corn storage and milling. In addition, two tchamahias and three axes were recovered from the room, suggesting it also served as a repository for ritual items. Tree-ring dates and ceramic evidence indicate initial construction of the room around 1090, with repairs to the roof at 1105, and San Juan use from the mid-1100s to 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="119">
    <desc>Room 119W is an original Chacoan room, of small size located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo, measuring 3.2 x 2.3 m. In all, 108 strata were identified in 119W; more than a third of the strata are floor-related. Other strata included structured trash, artificial fill, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature fill, and post-occupational deposits. The multiple floor designations can be grouped into perhaps eight total floors: four of San Juan and four of Chacoan origin. Fifty-five features were found in 118W, approximately half were Chacoan and half were San Juan age. Chacoan floors contained few features, consisting of doorways, vigas, latillas, and various pit structures. The San Juan era floors had features such as hearths, milling bins, roof-related structures, and pits. </desc>
    <unit id="0119W">
      <desc>Room 119W is an original Chacoan room, of small size located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo, measuring 3.2 x 2.3 m. In all, 108 strata were identified in 119W; more than a third of the strata are floor-related. Other strata included structured trash, artificial fill, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature fill, and post-occupational deposits. The multiple floor designations can be grouped into perhaps eight total floors: four of San Juan and four of Chacoan origin. Fifty-five features were found in 118W, approximately half were Chacoan and half were San Juan age. Chacoan floors contained few features, consisting of doorways, vigas, latillas, and various pit structures. The San Juan era floors had features such as hearths, milling bins, roof-related structures, and pits. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="120">
    <desc>Room 120W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo.  The room measures 5 x 3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no feature or strata were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0120W">
      <desc>Room 120W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo.  The room measures 5 x 3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no feature or strata were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="121">
    <desc>Room 121W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5 x 4.7 m. During in the San Juan era, it was converted into a kiva identified as Room 121A. Fifty-one strata were identified in 121W, including 4 distinct floors. The lowest two are Chacoan in origin, while the upper two may represent Chacoan or San Juan era floors. Twenty-one features were found in 121W. The room 121Z designation was used to track features and deposits from an occupation perhaps earlier than the Chacoan use of Room 121W. These remains were found below the earliest Chacoan floor and extended beneath the walls of the room. Room 121A is the San Juan kiva emplaced into Room 121W in the mid-1100s or early 1200s. The kiva measures 4.7 m in diameter. Room 121B is the northeast interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Room 121C is the southeast interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Room 121D is the northwest interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Room 121E is the northwest interstitial space next to the 121A kiva.</desc>
    <unit id="121W">
      <desc>Room 121W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5 x 4.7 m. During in the San Juan era, it was converted into a kiva identified as Room 121A. Fifty-one strata were identified in 121W, including 4 distinct floors. The lowest two are Chacoan in origin, while the upper two may represent Chacoan or San Juan era floors. Twenty-one features were found in 121W. San Juan age features included two burials, two postholes, and several pits, along with the ventilator for the 121A kiva. Chacoan features included two doorways, several hearths, pits, and a milling bin. Tree-ring dates indicate construction around 1090-1094 and repairs at 1105. Use of the space continued until the 121A kiva was built in the mid-1100s and used until the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121Z">
      <desc>RThe room 121Z designation was used to track features and deposits from an occupation perhaps earlier than the Chacoan use of Room 121W. These remains were found below the earliest Chacoan floor and extended beneath the walls of the room. Ten strata were found, including artificial fill layers used to build up the Chacoan floor, an occupational fill, feature fill, and a floor surface that extended well beyond the limits of the Chacoan room or the San Juan kiva. Four features were associated with 121Z including a hearth and three pits of unknown use.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121A">
      <desc>Room 121A is the San Juan kiva emplaced into Room 121W in the mid-1100s or early 1200s. The kiva measures 4.7 m in diameter. Eight strata were identified in 121A including a floor complex, occupational fill, and feature fill. A total of 23 features was associated with 121A including a central hearth, ventilation system, five evenly spaced pilasters, three niches, and a series of posts and postholes. An extensive mural was found on part of the kiva wall in Room 121A. The mural contained a number of motifs including anthropomorphic figures and geometric designs.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121B">
      <desc>Room 121B is the northeast interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Excavation identified 12 strata including feature-related units and trash deposits. The room had two features including a posthole and pit with ash and burned juniper.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121C">
      <desc>Room 121C is the southeast interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Excavation identified 5 Strata including three trash deposits, an occupational fill layer, and a floor surface. No features were found in the room and no tree-ring dates were obtained.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121D">
      <desc>Room 121D is the northwest interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Excavation identified only one stratum and no features.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="121E">
      <desc>Room 121E is the northwest interstitial space next to the 121A kiva. Excavation identified no strata and no features. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="122">
    <desc>Room 122 is an original Chacoan room located directly north of Room 121 in the southwest section of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (Room 122W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva (122A) that was emplaced into the Chacoan room. The Chacoan room is quite large, measuring by 8.9 by 5 m north-south and the San Juan kiva has a diameter of 5 m. The room and kiva were partially excavated during the project. Thirteen features were identified and 21 strata were defined across both rooms.</desc>
    <unit id="122W">
      <desc>Room 122 is an original Chacoan room located directly north of Room 121 in the southwest section of Salmon Pueblo. The room space comprises an original Chacoan room (Room 122W) in the 3rd tier of room from the back wall and a later San Juan era small kiva (122A) that was emplaced into the Chacoan room. The Chacoan room is quite large, measuring by 8.9 by 5 m north-south and the San Juan kiva has a diameter of 5 m. The room and kiva were partially excavated during the project. Thirteen features were identified and 21 strata were defined across both rooms.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="123">
    <desc>Room 123W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5 x 3.1 m and was subdivided late in the San Juan occupation into Rooms 123A and 123B. Room 123W had a Chacoan floor with evidence of considerable San Juan intrusion for burial purposes. Twenty-eight strata were identified in 123W  including structured trash, occupational fill, feature fill, construction debris, preconstruction layers, and several strata identified as structural floors. Ten features were recorded in Room 123W. Chacoan doorways built in the east and west walls were reused by the later San Juan occupants. Other features included a storage pit of Chacoan origin, two other pits, and five Chacoan age hearths. No features of purely San Juan origin were recorded in the room. Based on the architectural style, stratigraphy, and ceramic assemblage, Room 123W was likely constructed during the original Chacoan episode around 1090.</desc>
    <unit id="123W">
      <desc>Room 123W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5 x 3.1 m and was subdivided late in the San Juan occupation into Rooms 123A and 123B. Room 123W had a Chacoan floor with evidence of considerable San Juan intrusion for burial purposes. Twenty-eight strata were identified in 123W  including structured trash, occupational fill, feature fill, construction debris, preconstruction layers, and several strata identified as structural floors. Ten features were recorded in Room 123W. Chacoan doorways built in the east and west walls were reused by the later San Juan occupants. Other features included a storage pit of Chacoan origin, two other pits, and five Chacoan age hearths. No features of purely San Juan origin were recorded in the room. Based on the architectural style, stratigraphy, and ceramic assemblage, Room 123W was likely constructed during the original Chacoan episode around 1090. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="123A">
      <desc>Room 123A is the northern portion of subdivided 123W. It measures 3 x 2.3 m and is divided from 123B by a cobble-and-mortar wall built during the San Juan occupation. The six strata identified in Room 123A consist of post-occupational layers, roof-fall, structured trash, and a floor complex. Room 123A had just one feature - a milling bin. The room evidently functioned as a milling facility, with use for corn storage as well. Based on the architectural style, stratigraphy, and ceramic assemblage, Room 123A was created sometime after 1130 and before 1200.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="123B">
      <desc>Room 123B is the southern portion of subdivided 123W. It measures 3 x 2.3 m and is divided from 123A by a cobble-and-mortar wall built during the San Juan occupation. Only three strata were recorded in the room: two post-occupational layers and a structured trash deposit. Work ceased in the room early, and lower levels were never reached. Three features were found in Room 123B: two burials and the east-west wall that divided it from 123A. Clearly, the San Juan occupants used Room 123B to deposit trash and bury deceased individuals. Based on the architectural style, stratigraphy, and ceramic assemblage, Room 123B was created sometime after 1130 and before 1200.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="124">
    <desc>Room 124W is an original Chacoan residential room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.2 x 5.2 m. After 1130, a San Juan period kiva (Room 124A) was built into the Chacoan room. Room 124A is the San Juan kiva emplaced into Room 124W in the mid-late 1100s. Room 124B is the northwest interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. Room 124C is the northeast interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. Room 124D is the southeast interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. Room 124E is the southwest interstitial space next to the 124A kiva.</desc>
    <unit id="124W">
      <desc>Room 124W is an original Chacoan residential room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.2 x 5.2 m. After 1130, a San Juan period kiva (Room 124A) was built into the Chacoan room. Only four strata were identified in 124W, due to the disturbance of sediments during the construction of the San Juan kiva (124A). These strata included an occupational level and a Chacoan floor complex. Five features were recorded in 124W, including two Chacoan doorways, a milling bin, burial, and a hearth. Except for the burial, all features were Chacoan in origin. Given the room’s size and position in the pueblo, it probably served a habitation-living function during the Chacoan occupation. But, the thorough nature of later usage removed the vast majority of Chacoan features and deposits from the room. Chacoan construction of Room 124W appears to have occurred during the initial building episode at 1090. One tree ring date of 1072 was obtained. This is likely due to early activity in this part of the pueblo, as discussed under Room 124Z.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124Z">
      <desc>The 124Z designation was used to track features and deposits from an occupation earlier than the Chacoan use of Room 124W. These remains were found below the earliest Chacoan floor and extended beneath the walls of the room and the later San Juan kiva. Twenty-four strata were found including surfaces, pre-Chacoan deposits, and numerous feature-related strata. Twenty-five features were identified in 124Z including hearths, a bin, storage pits, roasting pits, postholes, cists, a burial, and walls. This diversity supports the concept of an earlier, pre-1090 occupation underlying the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. Tree-ring dates suggest a range of 1068-1072.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124A">
      <desc>Room 124A is the San Juan kiva emplaced into Room 124W in the mid-late 1100s. The kiva measures 5 m in diameter. Thirteen strata were identified in kiva 124A  including roof-fall, a floor complex, and feature-related deposits. Twenty features were recorded in the kiva. It had a central hearth, deflector, bench around its perimeter, ventilator tunnel and shaft, wall niches, probable sipapu, four evenly spaced pilasters, storage pit, and other pits of unknown purpose. The wall of the 124A kiva exhibited a mural with the design much simpler than what was found in the adjacent Room 121A kiva. Stratigraphy, ceramics, and the architectural style indicate that the kiva was built sometime in the mid-late 1100s and used into the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124B">
      <desc>Room 124B is the northwest interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. Excavation identified four strata including trash and construction-related deposits. No features were found. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124C">
      <desc>Room 124C is the northeast interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. No strata or features were identified. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124D">
      <desc>Room 124D is the southeast interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. No strata or features were identified. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="124E">
      <desc>Room 124E is the southwest interstitial space next to the 124A kiva. No strata or features were identified. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="125">
    <desc>Room 125W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo.  The room measures 4.7 x 3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were recorded and two strata were noted. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="125W">
      <desc>Room 125W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo.  The room measures 4.7 x 3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were recorded and two strata were noted. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="127">
    <desc>Room 127W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.4 x 2.9 m. It was constructed during the initial episode, around 1090, and a kiva was added during the later San Juan occupation (designated Room 127A). In all, 49 strata were identified in 127W; half were feature-related deposits. The San Juan strata included trash layers, roof-fall, and a floor complex. Around ten strata were mixed Chacoan and San Juan ceramics. Chacoan strata include a floor complex, artificial fill, and feature fill. One surface was determined to be pre-Chacoan in origin. Thirty-six features were associated with Room 127W. At least ten were San Juan in origin: five burials, two hearths, ash pits, and roofing material. The Chacoan age features include ash pits, hearths, a ritual feature with a ceramic bowl and a mano. The room was burned in the late 1100s or early 1200s, a burning event seen elsewhere across Salmon Pueblo. After this, Room 127W was converted into the 127A kiva. Room 127B is the southern (southeast and southwest) interstitial space around the 127A kiva ventilator tunnel and between the original Chacoan walls. Room 127C is the northeast interstitial space around the 127A kiva. Room 127D is the northwest interstitial space around the 127A kiva. Room 127E is the southeast portion of Room 127W.The 127Z designation was used to track deposits from a hypothetical occupation below the Chacoan use of Room 127W.</desc>
    <unit id="127W">
      <desc>Room 127W is an original Chacoan room located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 5.4 x 2.9 m. It was constructed during the initial episode, around 1090, and a kiva was added during the later San Juan occupation (designated Room 127A). In all, 49 strata were identified in 127W; half were feature-related deposits. The San Juan strata included trash layers, roof-fall, and a floor complex. Around ten strata were mixed Chacoan and San Juan ceramics. Chacoan strata include a floor complex, artificial fill, and feature fill. One surface was determined to be pre-Chacoan in origin. Thirty-six features were associated with Room 127W. At least ten were San Juan in origin: five burials, two hearths, ash pits, and roofing material. The Chacoan age features include ash pits, hearths, a ritual feature with a ceramic bowl and a mano. The room was burned in the late 1100s or early 1200s, a burning event seen elsewhere across Salmon Pueblo. After this, Room 127W was converted into the 127A kiva. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127A">
      <desc>Room 127A is a small San Juan kiva emplaced in 127W sometime after 1200. The kiva measures 3.4 m in diameter. Nine strata were identified including structured trash, roof-fall, a floor complex, feature fill, and a pre-occupational layer. Most features and artifacts were associated with the kiva floor. Ten features were associated with kiva 127A including a central hearth, a milling bin that had collapsed from the roof of 127W, a wall niche, and a ventilator tunnel and shaft. Many of the features typically found in San Juan style kivas at Salmon -- deflector slab or wall, bench, sipapu, and pilasters -- were not present in kiva 127A.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127B">
      <desc>Room 127B is the southern (southeast and southwest) interstitial space around the 127A kiva ventilator tunnel and between the original Chacoan walls. Five strata were identified in 127B:  roof-fall and artificial fill layers. Room 127B had one burial feature from the San Juan occupation. The burial was apparently interred after the 127A kiva was constructed and before the end of occupation of the site in the 1280s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127C">
      <desc>Room 127C is the northeast interstitial space around the 127A kiva. No notes or drawings were found in the Salmon archive. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127D">
      <desc>Room 127D is the northwest interstitial space around the 127A kiva. No notes or drawings were found in the Salmon archive. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127E">
      <desc>Room 127E is the southeast portion of Room 127W. It measures 1.5 x 1 m and was created during the San Juan period for use as a turkey pen. Six strata were defined, along with a single feature consisting of a wall. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="127Z">
      <desc>The 127Z designation was used to track deposits from a hypothetical occupation below the Chacoan use of Room 127W. A single stratum was assigned to this unit but no features were found.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="128">
    <desc>Room 128W is an original, long Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 11 x 2.2 m and was was divided in the San Juan period into two smaller rooms—128A and 128B. Excavations were restricted to the southern two-thirds of the room. No San Juan architectural modifications were encountered but San Juan burials and trash were found directly on its original floor. Seven strata were identified in 128W, including a floor unit, roof-fall, feature-related strata and pre-Chacoan strata. No strata were associated with the Chacoan occupation; apparently San Juan occupants used the room to the level of the deepest chacoan use. No features were identified but a large quantities of turkey bone and eggshell dating to the San Juan period were found. This suggests 128W was used as a turkey pen. Masonry style indicates construction during the initial episode, around 1090 and use into the 1280s.</desc>
    <unit id="128W">
      <desc>Room 128W is an original, long Chacoan room located in the southeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. It measures 11 x 2.2 m and was was divided in the San Juan period into two smaller rooms—128A and 128B. Excavations were restricted to the southern two-thirds of the room. No San Juan architectural modifications were encountered but San Juan burials and trash were found directly on its original floor. Seven strata were identified in 128W, including a floor unit, roof-fall, feature-related strata and pre-Chacoan strata. No strata were associated with the Chacoan occupation; apparently San Juan occupants used the room to the level of the deepest chacoan use. No features were identified but a large quantities of turkey bone and eggshell dating to the San Juan period were found. This suggests 128W was used as a turkey pen. Masonry style indicates construction during the initial episode, around 1090 and use into the 1280s. </desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="128A">
      <desc>Room 128A is the southern portion of the subdivided room 128W. It measures 5.2 x 2 m and was created during the late 1100s to early 1200s. Twelve strata were found in 128A, all of San Juan age. Two floors, occupational fill, and feature-related strata were identified. In all, 12 features were associated with 128A including many hearths, a burial, a storage cist, a turkey pen, a pit of unknown use, a vent window, and the wall separating 128A from 128B. These features indicate that the room had multiple functions. Turkeys were apparently kept in the room based on the turkey pit-pen feature and the turkey bone and eggshell recovered.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="128B">
      <desc>Room 128B is the northern portion of the subdivided room 128W. It measures 6.8 x 2.1 m and was created during the late 1100s to early 1200s. Six strata were identified in 128B, including three floors, an occupational unit, and a feature-related deposit. Room 128B had one pit feature recorded. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="129">
    <desc>Room 129W is an original Chacoan room of large size that measures 5.8 x 3.3 m and is located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room was heavily used by the Chacoans, perhaps initially as a residential room and later as a burial and trash repository. The later San Juan occupants also used the room as a trash depository. Room 129W was one of the most complex units at the site. It contained 244 defined stratigraphic units, and because of its size and complexity, excavations reached but did not complete clearing of the Chacoan floor. Its first story was constructed about 1090 and then its function shifted when an extensive internal milling bin facility was established. The Room 129W ground story was abandoned during the Chacoan occupation and became a repository for an exceedingly complex series of trash mounds. Trash deposition continued into the San Juan occupation. A San Juan floor above these trash deposits indicated a final function just before the room was totally destroyed by fire. Of the strata, more than half were structured trash deposits and were part of 19 separate trash mounds. The trash deposits were predominantly of Chacoan or mixed Chacoan–early San Juan age, with only a few dated to the later San Juan occupation. Other strata included several floor complexes, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature-related strata, and construction debris. In all, 129 features were associated with 129W. More than 50 relate to roofing and construction. Chacoan age features included five doorways, vent windows, four hearths, several milling bins, a macaw skeleton, two wall niches, and several floor pits of unknown function. San Juan features were somewhat less numerous, and beyond roofing features, they included a burial, caches, a modified doorway, and several trash mounds. Masonry indicates construction during the initial occupation, around 1090, and a long and complicate use-life of the room through the end of the Chacoan period and into the San Juan period.</desc>
    <unit id="129W">
      <desc>Room 129W is an original Chacoan room of large size that measures 5.8 x 3.3 m and is located in the southeast sector of Salmon Pueblo. The room was heavily used by the Chacoans, perhaps initially as a residential room and later as a burial and trash repository. The later San Juan occupants also used the room as a trash depository. Room 129W was one of the most complex units at the site. It contained 244 defined stratigraphic units, and because of its size and complexity, excavations reached but did not complete clearing of the Chacoan floor. Its first story was constructed about 1090 and then its function shifted when an extensive internal milling bin facility was established. The Room 129W ground story was abandoned during the Chacoan occupation and became a repository for an exceedingly complex series of trash mounds. Trash deposition continued into the San Juan occupation. A San Juan floor above these trash deposits indicated a final function just before the room was totally destroyed by fire. Of the strata, more than half were structured trash deposits and were part of 19 separate trash mounds. The trash deposits were predominantly of Chacoan or mixed Chacoan–early San Juan age, with only a few dated to the later San Juan occupation. Other strata included several floor complexes, roof-fall, occupational fill, feature-related strata, and construction debris. In all, 129 features were associated with 129W. More than 50 relate to roofing and construction. Chacoan age features included five doorways, vent windows, four hearths, several milling bins, a macaw skeleton, two wall niches, and several floor pits of unknown function. San Juan features were somewhat less numerous, and beyond roofing features, they included a burial, caches, a modified doorway, and several trash mounds. Masonry indicates construction during the initial occupation, around 1090, and a long and complicate use-life of the room through the end of the Chacoan period and into the San Juan period.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="130">
    <desc>Room 130W is the Great Kiva at Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the plaza, offset from the center of the pueblo. The center of the structure is aligned on a true-north axis with the center of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 14.5 m in diameter inside from wall to wall and 17.5 m outside. A total of 112 strata was identified in 130W. Of these, 82 are feature-specific strata, while the rest cover a broad spectrum of deposits: structured trash, roof-fall, post-occupational fill, artificial fill, and five floor complexes. Four floors were San Juan in age with the lowest being Chacoan in origin. In all, 103 features were recorded in the Great Kiva. Except for 49 postholes, all features date to or were modified during the San Juan occupation. Other related features include construction rocks, doorways, hearths, wall niches, ash pits, a bench encircling the kiva, a stone stairway, and roof support columns. Many of these features are focused on the two large floor vault (foot drum) features. The eastern floor vault had a small space within that has been interpreted as an offering pit; it contained numerous calcite beads, turquoise, and the core from a bighorn sheep horn. In the vicinity of both floor vaults were numerous burned, impressed corn cobs; more than 71 were mapped in the area around the eastern floor vault. These may represent corn mothers. Storage pits were present around the structure; they probably held food or other items consumed during the ceremonies. Although no tree-ring dates mark its initial construction, we can infer that it was built during the initial Chacoan occupation at Salmon (around 1090). The later occupants substantially modified the structure, building an encircling cobble berm to improve structural support, refacing the interior masonry, and replacing the entire roof in the spring or summer of 1263 with hundreds of beams cut over a nearly 20-year period.</desc>
    <unit id="130W">
      <desc>Room 130W is the Great Kiva at Salmon Pueblo. It is located in the plaza, offset from the center of the pueblo. The center of the structure is aligned on a true-north axis with the center of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 14.5 m in diameter inside from wall to wall and 17.5 m outside. A total of 112 strata was identified in 130W. Of these, 82 are feature-specific strata, while the rest cover a broad spectrum of deposits: structured trash, roof-fall, post-occupational fill, artificial fill, and five floor complexes. Four floors were San Juan in age with the lowest being Chacoan in origin. In all, 103 features were recorded in the Great Kiva. Except for 49 postholes, all features date to or were modified during the San Juan occupation. Other related features include construction rocks, doorways, hearths, wall niches, ash pits, a bench encircling the kiva, a stone stairway, and roof support columns. Many of these features are focused on the two large floor vault (foot drum) features. The eastern floor vault had a small space within that has been interpreted as an offering pit; it contained numerous calcite beads, turquoise, and the core from a bighorn sheep horn. In the vicinity of both floor vaults were numerous burned, impressed corn cobs; more than 71 were mapped in the area around the eastern floor vault. These may represent corn mothers. Storage pits were present around the structure; they probably held food or other items consumed during the ceremonies. Although no tree-ring dates mark its initial construction, we can infer that it was built during the initial Chacoan occupation at Salmon (around 1090). The later occupants substantially modified the structure, building an encircling cobble berm to improve structural support, refacing the interior masonry, and replacing the entire roof in the spring or summer of 1263 with hundreds of beams cut over a nearly 20-year period.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="131">
    <desc>Room 131W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Three doorway features were recorded and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="131W">
      <desc>Room 131W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5.8 x 2.9 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Three doorway features were recorded and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="132">
    <desc>Room 132W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 5.8 x 1.8 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="132W">
      <desc>Room 132W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo along Salmon’s eastern wall. The room measures 5.8 x 1.8 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features or strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="136">
    <desc>Room 136W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). Room 136W measures 3.9 x 1.9 m. The room was completely excavated. Nine strata were defined including trash deposits, floors, and feature strata. Three features, including two pit features and a cobble concentration, were associated with 136W. Room 136W was probably built to house a family that could not find space within the main pueblo. It postdates Chacoan construction and use of the site but lower deposits in the room (136Z) contained Chacoan pottery. perhaps 1110-1120, and then continued in use until the late 1100s or 1200s. Room 136Z is the designation applied to deposits below Room 136W.</desc>
    <unit id="136W">
      <desc>Room 136W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). Room 136W measures 3.9 x 1.9 m. The room was completely excavated. Nine strata were defined including trash deposits, floors, and feature strata. Three features, including two pit features and a cobble concentration, were associated with 136W. Room 136W was probably built to house a family that could not find space within the main pueblo. It postdates Chacoan construction and use of the site but lower deposits in the room (136Z) contained Chacoan pottery. perhaps 1110-1120, and then continued in use until the late 1100s or 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="136Z">
      <desc>Room 136Z is the designation applied to deposits below Room 136W. Eight strata were defined including trash deposits, fill, and two surfaces. One pit feature of unknown function was encountered. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="137">
    <desc>Room 137W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). No work was completed beyond exposing walls and the room’s size is unclear. No features were recorded. Four strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="0137W">
      <desc>Room 137W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). No work was completed beyond exposing walls and the room’s size is unclear. No features were recorded. Four strata were defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="138">
    <desc>Room 138W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room measuring 2.4 x 2.2 m, located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). Seven strata were encountered, including two floors, fill deposits, and early midden deposits. One hearth feature was found within the room. Room 138W was probably built to house a family that could not find space within the main pueblo. It appears to postdate Chacoan construction and use of the site, but lower deposits in the room (138Z) contained Chacoan pottery. The room may have been built during the latter part of the Chacoan period, perhaps 1110-1120, and then continued in use until the late 1100s or 1200s.</desc>
    <unit id="138W">
      <desc>Room 138W is a San Juan period shallow cobble-and-adobe room measuring 2.4 x 2.2 m, located in Salmon’s plaza east of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). Seven strata were encountered, including two floors, fill deposits, and early midden deposits. One hearth feature was found within the room. Room 138W was probably built to house a family that could not find space within the main pueblo. It appears to postdate Chacoan construction and use of the site, but lower deposits in the room (138Z) contained Chacoan pottery. The room may have been built during the latter part of the Chacoan period, perhaps 1110-1120, and then continued in use until the late 1100s or 1200s.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="138Z">
      <desc>The designation 138Z was applied to deposits below the floor of Room 138W. This area contained three strata and one pit feature.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="139">
    <desc>Room 139W was constructed during the San Juan period after 1130. It is attached to Room 124W and extends into Salmon’s plaza. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2 m and was completely excavated. Three strata were defined including a floor. No features were identified. The room probably served a storage function during the San Juan period.</desc>
    <unit id="139W">
      <desc>Room 139W was constructed during the San Juan period after 1130. It is attached to Room 124W and extends into Salmon’s plaza. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2 m and was completely excavated. Three strata were defined including a floor. No features were identified. The room probably served a storage function during the San Juan period. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="140">
    <desc>Room 140W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 68W. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were recorded. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="140W">
      <desc>Room 140W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 68W. The room measures 2.2 x 2.2. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were recorded. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="141">
    <desc>Room 141W was constructed during the San Juan period after 1130. It was an addition to Salmon Pueblo just to the west of Room 140W and consists of a round kiva (designated 141A). The kiva measures 2.5 m in diameter. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were recorded. Only one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="141W">
      <desc>Room 141W was constructed during the San Juan period after 1130. It was an addition to Salmon Pueblo just to the west of Room 140W and consists of a round kiva (designated 141A). The kiva measures 2.5 m in diameter. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were recorded. Only one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="142">
    <desc>Room 142W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 62W. The room measures 4.4 x 2.5. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features were noted and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="142W">
      <desc>Room 142W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 62W. The room measures 4.4 x 2.5. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two doorway features were noted and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="143">
    <desc>Room 143W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). In the San Juan period, a kiva (Room 143A) was added to the room. The Chacoan room (143W) measures 6.2 x 5.8 m and the later kiva (143A) was 5m in diameter. Four strata were defined as the upper portion of the room was excavated. One feature, a burial, was recorded. The limited data available suggest the room was used throughout Salmon’s 200-year history. </desc>
    <unit id="143W">
      <desc>Room 143W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). In the San Juan period, a kiva (Room 143A) was added to the room. The Chacoan room (143W) measures 6.2 x 5.8 m and the later kiva (143A) was 5m in diameter. Four strata were defined as the upper portion of the room was excavated. One feature, a burial, was recorded. The limited data available suggest the room was used throughout Salmon’s 200-year history. </desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="144">
    <desc>Room 144W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, north of Room 143W and connected to it via a doorway. The room measures 6.2 x 3.6. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="144W">
      <desc>Room 144W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, north of Room 143W and connected to it via a doorway. The room measures 6.2 x 3.6. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="145">
    <desc>Room 145W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, northwest of Room 143W. The room measures 5.5 x 3.3. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="145W">
      <desc>Room 145W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, northwest of Room 143W. The room measures 5.5 x 3.3. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="146">
    <desc>Room 146W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon. During the San Juan period, a small kiva (Room 146A) was added to the room. The Chacoan room (146W) measures 5.5 x 3.3 m and the later kiva (146A) was 3.3 m in diameter. Two strata were defined very limited work defining walls was completed in the upper portion of the room. No features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="146W">
      <desc>Room 146W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon. During the San Juan period, a small kiva (Room 146A) was added to the room. The Chacoan room (146W) measures 5.5 x 3.3 m and the later kiva (146A) was 3.3 m in diameter. Two strata were defined very limited work defining walls was completed in the upper portion of the room. No features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="147">
    <desc>Room 147W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 142W. The room constitutes a long, nearly 20 m, space that is  2.2 m wide; it was apparently never divided into smaller rooms. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were identified. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="147W">
      <desc>Room 147W was probably constructed towards the end of the Chacoan period at Salmon Pueblo. It was built as an addition to the Chacoan roomblock just west of Room 142W. The room constitutes a long, nearly 20 m, space that is  2.2 m wide; it was apparently never divided into smaller rooms. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were identified. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="148">
    <desc>Room 148W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). Room 148W measures 6.2 x 5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were identified. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="148W">
      <desc>Room 148W is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). Room 148W measures 6.2 x 5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and no features were identified. A single stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="149">
    <desc>Room 149W  is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.8 x 5.8 m. Three strata were defined as the upper portion of the room was excavated. Three features -- a burial and two doorways -- were recorded. The limited data available suggest the room was used throughout Salmon’s 200-year history. As little work was completed, limited feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="149W">
      <desc>Room 149W  is an original Chacoan room in the western sector of Salmon, west of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W). It measures 5.8 x 5.8 m. Three strata were defined as the upper portion of the room was excavated. Three features -- a burial and two doorways -- were recorded. The limited data available suggest the room was used throughout Salmon’s 200-year history. As little work was completed, limited feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="150">
    <desc>Room 150W is a San Juan period room in Salmon’s plaza discovered during the excavation of Unit 213P. The room was not fully exposed so its size is unclear. Nine strata were defined including a floor but no features were recorded. Limited feature, strata, photographic, and documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="150W">
      <desc>Room 150W is a San Juan period room in Salmon’s plaza discovered during the excavation of Unit 213P. The room was not fully exposed so its size is unclear. Nine strata were defined including a floor but no features were recorded. Limited feature, strata, photographic, and documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="151">
    <desc>Room 151W is the northern antechamber and entrance for Salmon’s Great Kiva (Room 130W). It measures 6 x 4 m and is located north of the kiva. It articulates with the Great Kiva by a narrow stone and wooden pole stairway. Thirty strata were identified in 151W, the majority related to the San Juan occupation of Salmon. Only one stratum was linked to the Chacoan occupation. Six floor complexes were identified but only half of these were continuous across the room space; the others represent replasterings of existing floors. Other strata consisted of a roof-fall layer, feature-specific strata, occupational fill, and a trash stratum. Seven features were noted in Room 151W, including hearths, an ash pit, and smaller pits of unknown function. Underlying the lowest floor in Room 151W were the remains of two cobble rooms that predated construction of the antechamber, designated Rooms 151B and Rooms 151C.</desc>
    <unit id="151W">
      <desc>Room 151W is the northern antechamber and entrance for Salmon’s Great Kiva (Room 130W). It measures 6 x 4 m and is located north of the kiva. It articulates with the Great Kiva by a narrow stone and wooden pole stairway. Thirty strata were identified in 151W, the majority related to the San Juan occupation of Salmon. Only one stratum was linked to the Chacoan occupation. Six floor complexes were identified but only half of these were continuous across the room space; the others represent replasterings of existing floors. Other strata consisted of a roof-fall layer, feature-specific strata, occupational fill, and a trash stratum. Seven features were noted in Room 151W, including hearths, an ash pit, and smaller pits of unknown function. Underlying the lowest floor in Room 151W were the remains of two cobble rooms that predated construction of the antechamber, designated Rooms 151B and Rooms 151C.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="151B">
      <desc>Room 151B was oriented north-south with a width of about 2 m and an undetermined length. Five strata were found: two floor surfaces and three feature-related deposits. Two small pit features were identified in the room. Given its position under the Great Kiva’s antechamber, it was built and apparently used prior to construction of the Great Kiva. Few feature, strata, photographic, and documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
    <unit id="151C">
      <desc>Room 151C was exposed to the west of 151B and apparently adjoined it. It measured about 2 m wide with an undetermined length. No separate strata or features were recorded for Room 151C. Few feature, strata, photographic, and documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="153">
    <desc>Room 153W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.4 x 5.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="153W">
      <desc>Room 153W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.4 x 5.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="154">
    <desc>Room 154W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 3.3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="154W">
      <desc>Room 154W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 3.3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="155">
    <desc>Room 155W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central  portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 3.3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="155W">
      <desc>Room 155W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central  portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 3.3 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="156">
    <desc>Room 156W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="156W">
      <desc>Room 156W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.5 x 2.2 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No features were identified and one stratum was defined. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="157">
    <desc>Room 157W is a San Juan period kiva built inside a square room frame and located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The kiva measures 4.4 m in diameter.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="157W">
      <desc>Room 157W is a San Juan period kiva built inside a square room frame and located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The kiva measures 4.4 m in diameter.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="158">
    <desc>Room 158W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 8.4 x 2.9 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and a single doorway feature was recorded in the north wall. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="158W">
      <desc>Room 158W is an original Chacoan room located in the east-central portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 8.4 x 2.9 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and a single doorway feature was recorded in the north wall. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="159">
    <desc>Room 159W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 3.6 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and a single doorway feature was recorded in the east wall. No strata were defined. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="159W">
      <desc>Room 159W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 3.6 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls and a single doorway feature was recorded in the east wall. No strata were defined. No feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records are available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="160">
    <desc>Room 160W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.2 x 5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only two strata were defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="160W">
      <desc>Room 160W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.2 x 5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only two strata were defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="161">
    <desc>Room 161W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.2 x 6.2m.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No strata or features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="161W">
      <desc>Room 161W is an original Chacoan room located in the northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 6.2 x 6.2m.  No work was completed beyond exposing walls. No strata or features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="162">
    <desc>Room 162W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two strata were defined but no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="162W">
      <desc>Room 162W is an original Chacoan room located in the northeast portion of Salmon Pueblo. The room measures 5 x 2.5 m. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Two strata were defined but no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="167">
    <desc>Room 167W was assigned to an unexcavated interstitial space for the Room 35A kiva in the  northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. No room size is available. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    <unit id="167W">
      <desc>Room 167W was assigned to an unexcavated interstitial space for the Room 35A kiva in the  northwest portion of Salmon Pueblo. No room size is available. No work was completed beyond exposing walls. Only one stratum was defined and no features were recorded. There are no feature, strata, photographic, or documentary records available for this room.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="004P">
    <desc>4P is a series of 1x1 m units that form a trench excavated into Salmon’s plaza. The trench runs mostly north-south with some extension on the east-west axis, in the area south of Rooms 60 and 68. One feature, consisting of a burial, was found in 004P and four strata were identified during excavations.</desc>
    <unit id="004P">
      <desc>4P is a series of 1x1 m units that form a trench excavated into Salmon’s plaza. The trench runs mostly north-south with some extension on the east-west axis, in the area south of Rooms 60 and 68. One feature, consisting of a burial, was found in 004P and four strata were identified during excavations.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="005P">
    <desc>5P is a series of 1x1 m units that form a trench excavated into Salmon’s plaza and running east-west, just south of Rooms 60 and 68. No features were found during work on the trench and five strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="005P">
      <desc>5P is a series of 1x1 m units that form a trench excavated into Salmon’s plaza and running east-west, just south of Rooms 60 and 68. No features were found during work on the trench and five strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="413P">
    <desc>413P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. No features were found during work in 413P but five strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="413P">
      <desc>413P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. No features were found during work in 413P but five strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="513P">
    <desc>513P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. Only one feature, a burial, was discovered in 513P. Only three strata were identified during excavations in 513P.</desc>
    <unit id="513P">
      <desc>513P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. Only one feature, a burial, was discovered in 513P. Only three strata were identified during excavations in 513P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="011P">
    <desc>11P is a very long plaza trench that runs from north-to-south from just south of Room 60A and ends roughly even with Salmon’s Great Kiva (Room 130W), roughly 35 m to the south. Not unexpectedly, this long trench revealed 18 features, including hearths, trash pits, ash pits, walls, and other features in Salmon’s plaza. Thirty-four individual strata were designed during excavation of the trench across Salmon’s plaza.</desc>
    <unit id="011P">
      <desc>11P is a very long plaza trench that runs from north-to-south from just south of Room 60A and ends roughly even with Salmon’s Great Kiva (Room 130W), roughly 35 m to the south. Not unexpectedly, this long trench revealed 18 features, including hearths, trash pits, ash pits, walls, and other features in Salmon’s plaza. Thirty-four individual strata were designed during excavation of the trench across Salmon’s plaza.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="014P">
    <desc>14P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza northwest of the Great Kiva (Room 130W).  Two features of Chacoan age (a hearth and a cobble feature) were found during excavations and 18 strata were designated in 14P.</desc>
    <unit id="014P">
      <desc>14P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza northwest of the Great Kiva (Room 130W).  Two features of Chacoan age (a hearth and a cobble feature) were found during excavations and 18 strata were designated in 14P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="015P">
    <desc>15P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and north of Room 150W, antechamber to the Great Kiva (Room 130W). The only feature encountered in 15P is a wall foundation for Room 150W. Nine stratigraphic units were designated during the excavation of 15P.</desc>
    <unit id="015P">
      <desc>15P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and north of Room 150W, antechamber to the Great Kiva (Room 130W). The only feature encountered in 15P is a wall foundation for Room 150W. Nine stratigraphic units were designated during the excavation of 15P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="016P">
    <desc>16P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 121W. A number of features were encountered during excavations in 16P including trash pits, other pits, a wall, and part of the ventilator system associated with the kiva in Room 121A. Thirty-five strata were designated in the course of work in 16P.</desc>
    <unit id="016P">
      <desc>16P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 121W. A number of features were encountered during excavations in 16P including trash pits, other pits, a wall, and part of the ventilator system associated with the kiva in Room 121A. Thirty-five strata were designated in the course of work in 16P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="017P">
    <desc>17P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in the middle of Salmon’s plaza on the west side, northwest of the Great Kiva and east of Salmon’s western roomblock. Two features were found in 17P including a hearth and a burial. Eighteen strata were designated in 17P.</desc>
    <unit id="017P">
      <desc>17P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in the middle of Salmon’s plaza on the west side, northwest of the Great Kiva and east of Salmon’s western roomblock. Two features were found in 17P including a hearth and a burial. Eighteen strata were designated in 17P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="018P">
    <desc>18P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 122W. Nine features were discovered in 18P including postholes and a burial. Thirty-two strata were identified in 18P.</desc>
    <unit id="018P">
      <desc>18P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 122W. Nine features were discovered in 18P including postholes and a burial. Thirty-two strata were identified in 18P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="019P">
    <desc>19P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 122W. Six features were identified in 19P including postholes, a pit, a storage pit, and part of a wall. Fifteen strata were designated during excavations in 19P.</desc>
    <unit id="019P">
      <desc>19P is a series of 1x1 m units excavated in Salmon’s plaza adjacent to and west of Room 122W. Six features were identified in 19P including postholes, a pit, a storage pit, and part of a wall. Fifteen strata were designated during excavations in 19P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="020P">
    <desc>20P is a long plaza trench that runs west from the midpoint of the Salmon plaza, south of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W), to a point just west of Room 121W and Unit 16P. Twenty-two features were found in 20P including hearths, ash pits, trash pits, a burial, and part of a wall. Thirty-nine strata were encountered during excavations in 20P.</desc>
    <unit id="020P">
      <desc>20P is a long plaza trench that runs west from the midpoint of the Salmon plaza, south of the Tower Kiva (Room 64W), to a point just west of Room 121W and Unit 16P. Twenty-two features were found in 20P including hearths, ash pits, trash pits, a burial, and part of a wall. Thirty-nine strata were encountered during excavations in 20P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="021P">
    <desc>21P is a trench excavated in Salmon’s plaza that runs from the edge of Salmon Pueblo, just south of Room 93W, to a point to the south where it intersects trench 20P. The trench had a variety of features including seed caches, trash pits, ash pits, hearths, and posthole. A total of 68 individual strata were designated during excavation of 21P.</desc>
    <unit id="021P">
      <desc>21P is a trench excavated in Salmon’s plaza that runs from the edge of Salmon Pueblo, just south of Room 93W, to a point to the south where it intersects trench 20P. The trench had a variety of features including seed caches, trash pits, ash pits, hearths, and posthole. A total of 68 individual strata were designated during excavation of 21P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="112P">
    <desc>112P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the central part of the Salmon plaza on the north-south line halfway between Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and Great Kiva (Room 130W). Only one feature, part of the wall of an unexcavated kiva in the plaza, was identified during work in 112P. Four strata were recognized during excavations in 112P.</desc>
    <unit id="112P">
      <desc>112P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the central part of the Salmon plaza on the north-south line halfway between Salmon’s Tower Kiva (Room 64W) and Great Kiva (Room 130W). Only one feature, part of the wall of an unexcavated kiva in the plaza, was identified during work in 112P. Four strata were recognized during excavations in 112P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="113P">
    <desc>113P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the western portion of the Salmon plaza several meters east of Room 6W. Two features, both sections of walls, were found during excavations in 113P. Five strata were designated during the work in 113P.</desc>
    <unit id="113P">
      <desc>113P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the western portion of the Salmon plaza several meters east of Room 6W. Two features, both sections of walls, were found during excavations in 113P. Five strata were designated during the work in 113P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="212P">
    <desc>212P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the central part of the Salmon plaza, north-northeast of the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and south of 112P. The only feature found in 212P was a Chacoan hearth. Seven strata were recognized during excavations in 212P.</desc>
    <unit id="212P">
      <desc>212P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the central part of the Salmon plaza, north-northeast of the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and south of 112P. The only feature found in 212P was a Chacoan hearth. Seven strata were recognized during excavations in 212P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="213P">
    <desc>213P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the western portion of the Salmon plaza several meters east of Room 6W and Unit 113P. No features were found and 13 strata were identified in 213P.</desc>
    <unit id="213P">
      <desc>213P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the western portion of the Salmon plaza several meters east of Room 6W and Unit 113P. No features were found and 13 strata were identified in 213P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="313P">
    <desc>313P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the west-central portion of the Salmon plaza, abutting Unit 14P and northwest of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). The only feature found in 313P was a trash pit. Twelve strata were designated during excavations.</desc>
    <unit id="313P">
      <desc>313P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the west-central portion of the Salmon plaza, abutting Unit 14P and northwest of the Great Kiva (Room 130W). The only feature found in 313P was a trash pit. Twelve strata were designated during excavations.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="413P">
    <desc>413P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. No features were found during work in 413P but five strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="413P">
      <desc>413P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. No features were found during work in 413P but five strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="513P">
    <desc>513P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. Only one feature, a burial, was discovered in 513P. Only three strata were identified during excavations in 513P.</desc>
    <unit id="513P">
      <desc>513P is a series of contiguous 1x1 m units excavated in the east-central portion of the Salmon plaza, roughly equidistant between the Great Kiva (Room 130W) and the eastern roomblock. Only one feature, a burial, was discovered in 513P. Only three strata were identified during excavations in 513P.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="001BW">
    <desc>001BW comprises a 1x1 m unit placed along Salmon’s back wall to help define it. No features were found in this very limited excavation unit and only one strata was designated.</desc>
    <unit id="001BW">
      <desc>001BW comprises a 1x1 m unit placed along Salmon’s back wall to help define it. No features were found in this very limited excavation unit and only one strata was designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="002BW">
    <desc>2BW is located north of Room 76W. The space comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Four pit features and an isolated human tooth were identified and 20 strata were defined.</desc>
    <unit id="002BW">
      <desc>2BW is located north of Room 76W. The space comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Four pit features and an isolated human tooth were identified and 20 strata were defined.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="003BW">
    <desc>3BW is located north of Room 78W. The unit comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Three pit features were identified and 13 strata were defined.</desc>
    <unit id="003BW">
      <desc>3BW is located north of Room 78W. The unit comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Three pit features were identified and 13 strata were defined.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="008BW">
    <desc>8BW is located north of Rooms 40W and 41W. The unit comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Three pit features, a collapsed balcony feature from Salmon’s back wall, and a seed cache were identified and 18 strata were defined.</desc>
    <unit id="008BW">
      <desc>008BW is located north of Rooms 40W and 41W. The unit comprises a series of 1x1 m excavation units dug to explore the area behind Salmon’s backwall. No Salmon Pueblo rooms were encountered during the work. Three pit features, a collapsed balcony feature from Salmon’s back wall, and a seed cache were identified and 18 strata were defined.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="SA09">
    <desc>SA09 comprises several 1x1 m units excavated in 1970 in the vicinity of Rooms 61A and 63W. (SA stands for &quot;Search Area&quot;) No features were identified and three strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="SA09">
      <desc>SA09 comprises several 1x1 m units excavated in 1970 in the vicinity of Rooms 61A and 63W. (SA stands for &quot;Search Area&quot;) No features were identified and three strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="SA11">
    <desc>SA11 comprises several 1x1m units excavated in 1970. (SA stands for &quot;Search Area&quot;) No features were identified and only two strata were discovered.</desc>
    <unit id="SA11">
      <desc>SA11 comprises several 1x1m units excavated in 1970. (SA stands for &quot;Search Area&quot;) No features were identified and only two strata were discovered.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="TT10">
    <desc>TT10 is a trench excavated in the western roomblock of Salmon Pueblo in 1973. Two features – a storage cist and hearth – were identified during work and 12 strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="TT10">
      <desc>TT10 is a trench excavated in the western roomblock of Salmon Pueblo in 1973. Two features – a storage cist and hearth – were identified during work and 12 strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="TT11">
    <desc>TT11 is short trench excavated in the area of Room 9W in 1973. No features were found in TT11 and only three strata were identified.</desc>
    <unit id="TT11">
      <desc>TT11 is short trench excavated in the area of Room 9W in 1973. No features were found in TT11 and only three strata were identified.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
  <room id="TT12">
    <desc>TT12 is a short trench excavated in Salmon’s west wing in 1973. No features were found and nine strata were designated.</desc>
    <unit id="TT12">
      <desc>TT12 is a short trench excavated in Salmon’s west wing in 1973. No features were found and nine strata were designated.</desc>
    </unit>
  </room>
</descriptions>
